感恩节快乐
Happy thanksgiving!
这边
Come here!
对  就这儿
Yeah! right here!
邦比  扔个火鸡给我
Toss me a bird, bumpy!
邦比
Woman 1: bumpy!
邦比  我们爱你
Yeah! woman 2: bumpy! we love you!
给你  亲爱的
There you go, darling.
这边  这边
Woman 3: over here! over here!
弗兰克  过这边来
Frank! come on!
过这边来
Come here.
这就是美国的问题所在
This is the problem. this is what's wrong with America.
它变得太大  大到让人迷失自我
It's gotten so big, you just can't find your way.
从前街角的杂货铺现在变成了超市
The grocery store on the corner is now a supermarket.
糖果店变成了麦当劳
The candy store is a mcdonald's.
还有这里  他妈的超级折扣店
And this place, a super-fucking discount store.
作为私营业主的那种自豪哪去了?
Where's the pride of ownership, huh?
私人服务哪去了?
Where's the personal service?
懂我意思吗  操
You see what I mean? shit.
他们哪来的权力去砍掉供应商
I mean, what right do they have, of cutting out the suppliers,
挤走中间商
Pushing out all the middlemen,
从厂家手里直接订货?
Buying direct from the manufacturer?
索尼  东芝
Sony this, toshiba that.
这些黄种人抢走了美国人的饭碗
All them chinks putting Americans out of work.
这就是现实
That's the way it is now.
你没事吧?
You all right?
你无法找到问题的症结
You can't find the heart of anything
也根本无从下手去解决问题
To stick the knife.
嘿
Hey!
有人吗?
Anybody here?
我能帮你吗?
Can I help you?
叫救护车
Call an ambulance.
别麻烦了  弗兰克
Forget it, frank.
没人管事
There's no one in charge.
叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
有人说邦比·强森是个好人
Some say bumpy johnson was a great man,
他的颂词中说他是个乐善好施的人
According to the eulogies, a giving man,
一个为人民服务的人
A man of the people.
没人在他们的悼词中
No one chose to use in their remembrances
把邦比·强森
The word most often associated with
和黑帮头目联系在一起
Ellsworth "bumpy" johnson, "gangster,"
在这个寒冷的下午  邦比·强森盖棺论定
Whose passing has brought a who's who of mourners on this chilly afternoon.
卢凯西黑帮老大  多米尼克·卡塔诺
Lucchese mob boss dominic cattano,
哈林区犯罪头子  尼克·巴恩斯
Harlem crime figure nicky barnes.
尼克  尼克
Nicky! nicky!
政界的精英们也纷纷出动
From the political arena,
纽约市长来了
The governor has come down, the mayor of new york,
警察局长  体育  娱乐界的明星都到了
And chief of police and commissioner, sports and entertainment luminaries.
邦比·强森  终年62岁
Reporter 2: bumpy johnson, age 62 when he passed,
统治哈林区达40年的民间英雄
Was a folk hero among harlem locals for over four decades.
被一些人赞为哈林区的罗宾汉
Regarded by some as the robin hood of harlem,
另一些人认为他是残忍的罪犯
By others as a ruthless criminal...
我不明白
I don't understand, you know.
我原以为邦比会有更大的发展
I would've thought that bumpy would put out a better spread, you know?
-要来点什么?  -不  谢谢
You want something? no, thanks.
在我的葬礼上我想要鸡翅
I want chicken wings at my funeral.
尼克·巴恩斯  瞧瞧是谁来了?
All right, nicky barnes. who is that?
他不知道是什么打中了他
He didn't know what hit him, you know what I'm saying?
我只管对着他的脸不停开枪
I just kept popping him in the face 'cause that's what I do.
我没有火  你有火吗?
I don't have a lighter. you have a light?
还行吧?
Okay?
很好
That's very good.
弗兰克
Hey, frank.
顺便帮我去拿个火
Go get me a light while you're at it.
谢了
Appreciate it.
卡塔诺
Don cattano.
罗斯  你好吗?
Hey, how you doing, rossi?
很好
Good.
要杯酒么先生?
Would you like a drink, sir?
给他杯威士忌加冰
Give him a scotch on the rocks.
过来
Come on. come on.
弗兰克  我知道你不好受
I know you're hurting, frank.
我也不好过
So am I.
我没事
I'm all right.
-你真没事?  -是的
You gonna be all right? yeah.
我确定邦比没对你说起  但他要我保证
I'm sure bumpy didn't say anything to you, but he made me promise
如果他出事了
That if anything ever happened to him,
我将保证你衣食无忧
That I should make sure that you want for nothing.
非常感谢
I appreciate that.
在这个房间有一半的人都欠邦比的钱
You know, half the people in this room owed bumpy money when he died.
他们以为我会忘记  但我会把帐收回来
They think I'm gonna forget to collect, but I'm gonna get that money.
哦  精神可嘉  放手去做吧
Well, that's the spirit. go get 'em.
罗伯特先生  到起诉席就坐
Mr. roberts, taking the prosecution's side,
告诉我们物证  辩论  判断是什么
Give us us v. mead, subject, issues, what the determination was
和这些东西对我们意味着什么
And what it means to us today.
同学们请注意听  你们将要质询罗伯特先生
Class, you'll be critiquing Mr. roberts, so pay attention.
我讨厌被叫到名字
I hate hearing my name called, you know?
那意味着我要站到前面去  转过身
It means I gotta get up in front of the class, I gotta turn around,
而且我明白他们每个人都知道的比我多
And I know every one of those people there, they know more than I do.
人最怕的不是死亡而是当众演讲
The number one fear of people, it ain't dying, it's public speaking.
这让我我身体不舒服  我想吐
I get physically ill, I wanna throw up.
这可是你谋生之路啊
And that's what you wanna do for a living.
我不想那样  我想闪人
No, I don't wanna be like that, man, I wanna beat it.
那么  这次我来做?
So, should I do this?
不  我来  我们高中就认识了
No, he'll take it from me, he knows me. I've known him since high school.
-从高中起?  -早上好
From high school? good morning. yeah.
如果他不接  扔进去就可以
He doesn't take it, just throw it in. it's good service.
-扔进去?  -对
Throw it in? all right. yeah.
-你好吗  苏西?  -嘿  杰
What's up, susie? hey, jay.
-你好啊  宝贝  -我很好
How you doing, baby? all right.
准备好没?
All right. ready?
他的头在这  砸他
Hey! that's his head!
我还把你当朋友  混蛋
You're supposed to be my friend, asshole!
我发誓  瑞奇  我不知道是你
I swear to god, richie, I didn't know it was you.
否则绝不会关门夹你的手
I would never slam a door on your hand, knowingly.
你他妈是咬了我的手
You bit my fucking hand.
你怎么发起传票来了?
What are you doing serving subpoenas, anyway?
-我们欠县里钱  -县里?
We're on loan to county. county?
-油水挺足的吧?  -去你妈的
How's that working out for you? hey, fuck you.
对不起  这传票我收下了  到此为止吧
Hey, I'm sorry. consider me served. can we leave it there?
你这可是袭警  算了?  没那么容易
Assault on a police officer? I don't think so.
看在老交情上  我能干点什么?
Hey, for old times' sake. what can we do?
你们要什么?  我能给你什么?
What do you want? what can I give you?
杰  持致命武器伤人能判多久?
What do you get for assault with a deadly weapon, jay?
最少5年  -5年
Five years minimum. five years.
哥们别这样  你们要什么  要谁?
Guys, come on. no, guys. what do you want? who do you want?
你有谁?
Who do you got?
你要找大埃尔的会计吗?  我给你找出来
You want big al's bookie? you want his accountant? I'll give him to you.
停停停
Stop, stop, stop.
他在那
There he is.
那个会计在那
That's him. that's the bookie.
好的  卡洛  下车  滚
All right, carlo, get lost.
-快下车  -就在这下?
Get out of the car.
-这...还是不要吧  -快  我们走
This is... I'd rather not. come on. let's go.
别紧张
Take it ease.
跟车还是跟人?
Want to stay with him or the car?
看看谁来取车
Let's see who comes for the car.
认为他在耍我们?
Think he made us?
你申请了搜查令吧  在哪?
You called in the warrants, right? so, where are they?
我刚打电话申请的
I just called, man.
我打完电话走回来  才过了10秒钟
I called and walked back here and 10 seconds has gone by.
杰  我看到他拿着票据
I saw him with the slips, jay.
他拿着杂货袋而已  里面有什么你又不知道
You saw policy slips? you saw grocery bags. you don't know what's in 'em.
少废话  我知道  你也知道里头装的什么
Yes, I do and so do you. don't give me that bull.
你急什么?  过半小时搜查令就到
What's the rush, richie? half an hour, the warrant will be here.
-我晚要上夜校  -是吗?  那要错过了
I got night school, all right? guess you're gonna miss it.
-操  走  -你确定?
Fuck this. come on. you sure?
确定  走
Yeah, I'm sure. let's go.
操
Fuck.
-杰  -干嘛
Jay. yeah?
操
Fuck.
亲爱的听众们  大家都爱这个秀
Wbz, honey bunch, the show they all love!
这里是杰佛森周六脱口秀
It's the groovy sound of the jefferson kaye saturday night show.
接下来是新闻时间
Dig, honey, it's coming up time for news.
这里是WBZ广播电台
Jumping on the ceiling, wallpaper peeling on wbz.
别走开  我们的节目10点开始  10点见
Stick around, the jace-man's got 10. back in 10.
这可不是零花钱  知道吗?
It's not just a couple of bucks, all right?
从原则上讲是一样的
It's the same thing in principle.
我们现在是在按原则办事吗?
Oh, are we talking principles?
瑞奇  一个把这么多钱上交的警察
Richie, a cop who turns in this kind of money, says one thing.
肯定会告发其他警察收黑钱  我们以后还用混?
He turns in cops who take money. we'll be fucking pariahs.
反正我们里外不是人
Yeah, well, then we're fucked both ways.
如果我们留下这笔钱就不会这样
Not if we keep it. only if we don't, then you're right, we're fucked.
只要我们留下钱就没事
But not if we keep it.
靠  现在是天上掉馅饼啊
God damn it, man! did we ask for this?
我们有拿抢指着人说"抢钱"吗?
Did we put a gun to someone's head and say, "give us your money"?
警察会杀了那些他们不信任的警察
Cops kill cops they can't trust.
我们不能上交
We can't turn it in, man.
你相信吗?
Can you believe that?
有多少?
How much is it?
九十八万七千美元
$987,000.
其他的钱呢?
Well, what happened to the rest of it?
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing
当着大家的面数钱?
Counting it out here in front of everybody?
你发神经了?
Are you nuts?
装回袋子里  贴上封条  放财务室去
Get it back in the bags, seal them up and down into the property room.
操他的假清高
You fucking boy scout.
干嘛?  干嘛?
What? what?
特普探长请在这签名
Detective trupo, sign here.
你们做好发大财的准备吗?
You guys ready to make a lot of fucking money?
-当然  -是的
Man 1: always. man 2: hell, yeah.
哦...
Fucking a.
看这个
Oh, look at this.
给
There you go.
-看看这个  -真漂亮
All right, look at this. man 2: fucking beautiful.
还有3条船
There's three more boats.
别留下任何东西
Hey, don't lose any of that shit.
-我知道  -小心
Man 1: I know. all right, be careful.
只要够试剂测试用就可以了
Hey! just enough for the reagent test.
少放点
A little less.
这是从法国运过来的毒品
This is the french connection dope.
艾迪和索尼从我们这拿走很多这样的货
Kilos of the same dope eddie egan and sonny grosso took from us.
警察抓到了  逮捕了每个人
The cops seize it, arrest everyone,
后来把毒品从证物室拿出来
Then they start taking it out of the evidence room,
掺入很多其它的东西再卖回给我们
Whacking it down to nothing and selling it back to us.
靠这个他们基本控制了整个市场
They basically control the market with it.
罗斯先生  我有惊喜给你
Mr. rossi, I have a surprise for you.
他们干这个有些年头了  靠我们的毒品发财
They've been doing it for years now. they live off it, our dope.
你有何想法?
What do you think?
弗兰克  这世界到底怎么了?
What the fuck is happening to the world, frank?
那些该死的骗子
Those fucking crooks.
我为邦比感到难过
Yeah. sad about bumpy.
哈林区永远都不会再和从前一样了
Things are never gonna be the same in harlem.
在外面没人敢惹你  因为邦比搞定了一切
You walk down the street, nobody bothers you 'cause bumpy was making sure of it.
来一斤
Half a key.
现在过得怎样?
How is your day now?
一片混乱  人人为己
It's chaos. every gorilla for hisself.
操
Motherfucker!
这可怎么活呀?  黑社会必须要有秩序
Who can live like that? there has to be order.
在意大利黑帮绝不会这样
That would never happen with italians.
秩序高于任何人的生命
More important than any one man's life, is order.
弗兰克
Frank.
请进  克劳德  坐
Hey. come on in, claude. sit down.
-你好吗?  -还好
How y'all doing, huh? good.
你在那看见内特了对吗?
So, you see nate over there? yeah?
嗯  经常看见他
Yeah, all the time.
-内特无处不在  -恩  -他是好人
Nate is everywhere. he's good. yeah.
-他还在那?  -对  他现在有家夜总会
He's still over there? yeah. he's got himself a club now.
-在哪里  西贡?  -曼谷
Okay. whereabouts, saigon? bangkok.
曼谷?  我想他不会回美国了
Bangkok? I don, t think he, s ever coming home.
走
Come on.
免费招待我们的兵哥哥
On the house, for our boys in uniform.
谢谢你  甜心  你真好
Thank you, sugar. that's very kind.
谢弗兰克吧
Thank frank.
谢谢  弗兰克
Thanks, frank.
放松
Just relax.
这玩意儿得分几次注射
You have to boot this shit a couple of times.
警察总是往里头掺东西  卖给我们这破玩意儿
The cops keep cutting it, selling the shit.
我没什么好说的  价格合适
I don't want to say anything, cause the price is right,
可越南那边的货
But that shit in nam is way,
可比这玩意儿强多了
Way heavy.
弗兰克  你没看到那个收钱的钱罐?
Did you ain't seen the jar, frank, hmm?
我想你明明从它前面经过
I think you walked right past it.
难道要我在上头贴上标签不成?
The money jar, frank. what do I gotta do, put a fucking sign on it?
看看这黑鬼  你应该知道
Look at this nigger right here. you know, frank,
邦比不再拥有116街区了
bumpy don't own 116th no more.
哈林区已经没有邦比的地盘
bumpy don't own no real estate in harlem right now.
现在我是地主  租金是20%
I'm the landlord and the lease is 20%% .
那就别再卖毒品了 找份正当工作
Look, don't sell dope then, frank. get a real job.
你需要工作  那不就是你需要的么?
You need a fucking job, frank? hmm? is that what you need?
你可以帮我干活
Well, you can come work for me.
好不?  帮我开车  开门什么的
Okay? you can drive me around, huh? you can open my doors.
鞍前马后  端茶递水
Huh? "yes, sir", "no, sir", "right away, sir", "anything you want, massa johnson".
20%
Twenty percent.
我的利润也就20%  谭哥
Twenty percent is my profit, tango.
如果都给你我就一点都不剩了
If I give you that, then what do I got left? nothing, man.
抽20%我就没有活路了
Twenty percent puts me out of business,
你认识的所有人都被逼得会走投无路
And every somebody you know out of business.
做事要守规矩  谭哥  你这是不守规矩
There's legitimate ways of doing things, tango, and then there's this way.
邦比在时都不会收20%
Not even bumpy took 20%% .
邦比已经翘辫子了
bumpy's fucking dead.
你这家伙
My man.
20%是吧?
Twenty percent?
那我就给20%  德克  我们走
Twenty percent. doc, let's go.
吐  干的好  坐
Out. good job. sit.
领导者就像牧羊人
A leader, like a shepherd,
他把最敏捷的羊打头阵
He sends his fastest nimble sheep, out front.
其他的就会跟着走
And the others will follow.
牧羊人静静地跟在头羊后面走
While the shepherd, he walks quietly behind it.
好孩子  这边
Here, boy! here we go. right here.
拿过来
Bring it here. yeah.
牧羊人在需要的时候
Now he's got the stick, and the cane, he'll use it!
使用手中的赶羊棍
If he has to.
但大多时候不需要
But most times he doesn't have to.
他不动声色却控制着整个羊群
He moves the whole herd quietly.
他们有什么权力砍掉供应商?
What right do they have cutting out the supplier?
和中间商  直接进货
The middleman. buying direct.
让美国人失业
Putting Americans out of work.
弗兰克  这就是现实
That's the way it is now, frank.
这就是现实
That's the way it is.
现在越南的毒品问题不只是大麻
The drug problem in vietnam is more than marijuana.
据估计估计有三分之一
At this point, it is estimated that one third
的美国士兵吸食
Of American troops are experimenting
鸦片和海洛因
With opium and heroin.
权威人士称他们已没收
The authorities say they have confiscated
大量大麻  海洛因何迷幻药等毒品
Large quantities of marijuana, heroin and pills.
每个通过这扇门的人和车辆都会
Every person and every vehicle going through the gates
受到彻底搜查
Is subject to a thorough shakedown.
士兵们在曼谷  西贡等地的休闲场所
Soldiers have access to the drugs at many rest and relaxation spots
很容易获得各种毒品
In bangkok, saigon and other areas throughout vietnam and thailand.
官员称廉价高纯度海洛因
Officials say the easy availability, relatively cheap cost
在西贡和远东地区广泛流通
And high purity of heroin throughout saigon and the far east,
导致士兵门吸食海洛因成风
Is leading to an epidemic of heroin addiction among us soldiers.
-接线员  -国际长途
Operator. yeah, international.
-城市?  -曼谷
What city? bangkok.
-知道国家代码吗?  -376
You know the country code? yeah, 376.
头三分钟的收费是...
For the first three minutes, it'll be...
我知道  我知道  我知道
I got it, I got it. I got it.
你好
Hello?
兄弟  需要帮忙吗?
Soul brothers. hey, can I help you?
内特
Nate.
-我认识你吗?  -是我
Do I know you? yeah, it's me.
我是你堂兄啊
Your cousin, negro.
给自己买点新衣服
Go on, get yourself a new suit.
我真地很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
瑞奇  少来了
Oh, please, richie.
今天实在走不开  我下周接他可以不?
It couldn't be avoided. I'll take him next weekend, all right?
我们要搬家了
We're moving.
什么?  去哪?
What? where?
去圣里吉斯  你关心吗?
The st. regis. what do you care?
去我妹妹那
To my sister's.
-妹妹?  在拉斯维加斯?  -对
Your sister's? in vegas? yeah.
你不能走  总之不能带走麦克
You are not moving to las vegas. not with michael, anyway.
那怎么办?  留给你?  瞧你现在这德行
What am I supposed to do with him, leave him with you? there's a picture.
嘿  别闹
Hey, guys! be cool.
罗莉  拉斯维加斯不是养孩子的地方
Laurie, las vegas is not the kind of place that you raise a kid.
那这儿环境好?  和你的狐朋狗友一块?
Oh, like this is a good environment? and around your friends?
那我什么时候才能见我的儿子?
When am I supposed to see my boy?
这个周末  还有上个周末
This weekend. last weekend.
该死
God damn it.
我刚才已经礼貌地要你们闭嘴
Hey! I asked you nice to shut up, right?
别敬酒不吃吃罚酒
Now I'm gonna have to kill you.
不然我一枪打爆你的头
I swear I will pull out my gun and put a bullet in your fucking heads!
现在停下来把玻璃捡走
Now stop what you're doing and pick up the glass!
冷静点  哥们  别激动
Calm down, man. okay, be cool.
真他妈疯子
Fucking crazy, man.
你没带枪
You don't have a gun.
你确定?
You sure?
你疯了 瑞奇
You are crazy, richie.
你的生活中根本就没我们的位置
You don't have room for us.
法庭见
I'll see you in court.
麦克  过来
Come on, michael.
和爸爸拜拜
Say bye to your dad.
过来  孩子
Get over here. hey, kiddo.
下周见好吗?  我们一起找点事儿做
I'll see you next week, all right? we'll do something.
我们去买冰淇淋
Let's get you an ice cream.
你们还有10分钟  10分钟
You have 10 minutes remaining. ten minutes.
摇啊  宝贝  摇啊  摇啊
Shake it, baby. shake it, shake it, shake it.
宝贝  别告诉我5美元才脱这么点
Oh, come on, girl. don't tell me $5 don't get me a little something.
就这个破地方还这么贵?
Can you dig that it costs money to be here?
来吧宝贝
Oh, come on, girl.
弗兰克   你想要多少
How much you want, frank?
告诉他我要100公斤
Tell him I want 100 keys.
弗兰克  没人能单独供你那么多货
Frank, ain't nobody I know can get you that much personally, all right?
你那也有一块是混合的
You're gonna have to piece it together from several sources,
而且还不是100%纯度的
And it's not gonna be 100%% pure.
那我不要
I don't want that.
弗兰克  我知道你不想要什么
I know what you don't want, frank,
但你现在需要做的是
But look, what you're gonna need is to get
找到潮州帮  还有九龙帮  西贡帮
To the chiu-chou syndicate, all right?
如果他们愿意和你合作的话
Cholon, saigon. if they're gonna deal with you at all.
我知道  但这样做已经太晚了
I understand that, but by then it's gonna be too late.
货已经被掺假  我要找到他们的货源
It'll be already chopped up. I wanna go get it where they go get it from.
我要直接找到源头
I wanna go to the source.
那么你想单干?
So, you're gonna go get it yourself?
不行吗?
Why not?
我远道而来
Huh? I came this far.
你想走进这该死的丛林去?
You're gonna go into the motherfucking jungle?
看看周围  我现在已经在丛林中了
I'm in the jungle. look around.
他们都在吃蟑螂一样的恶心东西
They're eating these roaches and whatever that is.
兄弟  我说的是蛇这样的东西
Nigga, I'm talking about snakes, all right?
还有老虎  越共
I'm talking about tigers, I'm talking about vietcong,
那里的蚊子会咬烂你屁股
I'm talking about mosquitoes that'll fucking kill your ass.
你现在还要去丛林?
You wanna go into the jungle?
去
We're going.
-操  走  -我们去
Fuck it. let's go. we're going.
-干嘛不去?  -走
Why not? let's go.
弗兰克
Hey, frank.
这一区被国民党封锁着
This whole spot's locked down by the kuomintang,
蒋介石的残余部队
General chiang kai-shek's defeated army.
你怎么把货带到美国去?
How would you get it into the states?
别担心那个
You ain't got to worry about that.
你在那边为谁工作?
Who do you work for in there?
这也不是你要担心的
You ain't got to worry about that, either.
那你是谁?
Who are you, really?
弗兰克卢卡斯  护照上写得很清楚
Frank lucas, says it right there in my passport.
我意思是你代表谁?
I mean, who you represent?
我自己
Me.
带100公斤海洛因进美国
You think you're going to take 100 kilos of heroin into the us,
而且没有任何后台  你觉得别人会让你这么干?
And you don't work for anyone? someone is going to allow that?
对  我觉能行
That's right.
首次交易以后
After this first purchase,
如果你没有被马赛的进口商
If you are not killed by marseille importers,
或他们在美国的人杀了
Or their people in the states,
接下来怎么办?
Then what?
我保证购买量将会越来越大
Then there will be more, much more, I guarantee it.
如果你不介意  下次我就不亲自来了
And if it's all the same to you, I don't wanna have to drag my ass up here no more.
当然不介意
Of course not.
以后都自己人了啊
My man.
知己  对吧?  是知己
Soul brother, huh? soul brother.
五万美元  给飞行员和那边接货的人应该够了
Fifty grand. it's gonna cover them and the pilot and the boys on the other end.
给他们十万
Give them a hundred.
五万就够了  弗兰克
Fifty is gonna cover it, frank.
我叫你给他们十万  这些都给他们  拿着
Give them a hundred, give them the whole thing. here.
听着
And look,
我就这些了  如果那批毒品没运到的话 ...
That's all I got. so, if that dope don't arrive for any reason...
别怪我翻脸不认人  我很忙  明白?
Hey, listen, cousin or no cousin, I'm a busy man, all right?
到时我可没时间参加你们的葬礼
I ain't got no time to be going to nobody's funeral.
一装上飞机  我就通知你
I'll let you know when it's in the air.
好样的
My man.
操
Fuck.
-瑞奇?  -请讲
Richie? yeah.
这狗娘养的把我害惨了
This fucking guy made me.
我也不知道他是怎么回事  反正这次真被他害惨了
I don't know how he did, but he did.
他居然想拿枪
He went for his gun.
我不得不杀了他
I had to do it, man.
听到枪声  外面有一百多人围来
There's 100 people out there that heard the shots.
你得帮帮我  你得做点什么
You gotta help me. you gotta do something.
亲爱的
Baby.
你在哪里  杰?
Where are you, jay?
我也不知道
That's the problem.
紧急呼叫  我需要帮助
Dispatch, I got a 10-13. I got a 10-13.
收到  你在哪里
Copy that. what's your 20?
二号楼
Tower two.
一号公寓
Apartment 1g.
肯特和韦斯特都参加了这次行动
Kent and west in the projects.
请问你是哪位
Identify yourself, please.
我是瑞奇·罗伯特警官
Detective richie roberts.
很抱歉  所有分队都不在这区域
That's a negative. I got no units in that area.
狗屎
Bullshit.
请保持线路畅通  我随时需要帮助
Please put the call out again. I'm gonna need assistance.
罗伯特警官  我现在人手不够
Detective roberts, I got no units in that area.
实在没有办法了
That's a negative.
我可没说警察　明白我意思吗
I didn't mention no cops. know what I'm saying?
明白吗
You know what I'm saying?
我要把这小子抓出来  踢他个屁股开花
Man 1: I'll get the motherfucker! kick his ass!
白种垃圾  你要对这负责
Man 2: yo, cracker, you gonna pay for this shit!
你小子要去哪里啊? 你小子要滚哪去啊 ?
Man 3: where the fuck you going? where the fuck you going?
你小子要做什么?
What you gonna do, motherfucker?
冷静  大家请冷静
Hey, hey, be cool. be cool, all right?
我会调查的  看发生什么事了
I'll find out what's going on in here.
瑞奇
Richie.
把门打开啊!
Open the door!
他妈的  把门打开啊!
Open the motherfucking door!
支援人员在哪?
Where's your backup?
你个白种垃圾
You motherfucking cracker!
没有支援吗  怎么回事啊
You got no backup? why is that?
你总得出来的  操
You gotta come out sometime, motherfucker!
用绷带把他的颈部包起来
Bandage his neck.
瑞奇  他已经死了啊
Richie, he's dead.
我知道他早死了
I know he's fucking dead, right.
把他脖子包起来  头弄干净
Bandage his neck, clean up his head,
让他坐起来  靠在担架上  把眼睛弄开
Prop him up on the gurney so he's sitting and open his fucking eyes.
把门打开!
Open this fucking door!
好了吗  我们走吧
All right? let's go.
操
Fuck.
行了  把他弄干净
All right, clean him up.
好了  现在怎么办?
Paramedic 2: okay. where's the solution?
-嘿  -嘿
Hey. huh?
该死的!  把门打开啊
God damn it, open this fucking door!
-把你的枪给我  -什么?
Give me your gun. what?
把枪给我
Give me your gun.
滚出来  给我滚出来
Get your punk ass out here, man!
-警标带了吧?  -是的
You have your badge? yeah.
我要宰了你个兔崽子!
I'm gonna kill that son of a bitch!
-你们准备好了吗  -恩
You guys ready? uh-huh.
好!  那就一直往前走
Okay. just keep moving forward.
-你还好吧?  -恩
You all right? yeah.
出来了!  他们出来了!
It's okay! it's okay!
我们要把他送去医院
We're taking him to the hospital.
大家请后退!  请让一下!
Everybody, step back! step back!
他没什么事
He's all right.
他没事的  我们会照顾好他的
He's okay. we're taking care of him.
请让一让  请让让
Step back. step back.
没事了  大家请后退
Everything's fine. just stand back.
他没事的
He's all right.
他还活着
He's alive.
里面发生什么事了
What happened inside?
我们要送他去医院
We're taking him to the hospital.
谢谢你  兄弟
Thanks, man.
操
Fuck.
那个混蛋居然用枪指着我  真不敢相信
That asshole pulled a piece on me, man. can you fucking believe it?
他用枪指着警察?
He pulls a piece on a cop?
不是我杀死他  就是他杀了我  我没选
I had to do it, man. kill or be killed.
这什么世界啊
Fucking crazy world, right?
你们在做什么任务?
What the fuck were you doing in the projects?
在调查一些东西  你知道的  老兄
Investigating stuff, man, you know,
诚如你的指示  我们先搜人
Just like you taught me. checking on guys,
追查下去  再把线索连起来
Following things up, putting the pieces together.
那混球卖毒品  真是个人渣
That guy was a dealer. a fucking dealer. scum of the earth.
那家伙没用枪顶着警察  杰
That guy didn't pull a gun on a cop, jay.
他是拿枪顶着瘾君子
That guy pulled a gun on a junkie,
这个瘾君子要抢劫他
A junkie who was trying to rob him.
你他妈的说什么?
What the fuck you say?
操  你小子在做什么啊
What the fuck, man? what are you doing, man?
你他妈的这是什么啊?
What the fuck is that?
那是我的钱
That's my fucking money, man!
我赚来的  它是我的
I earned this shit. that's mine!
-这是我做警察的工钱  -这他妈的又是什么?
I earned it doing good cop work! what the fuck is this?
做好警察的卖命钱!
Good cop work!
-你杀人了  -我出生入死赚来的钱
You murdered a guy! I earned it getting shot at!
你杀人了
You murdered a guy!
你杀了他  抢了他的钱
You murdered him, you robbed his money,
却叫我帮你解围
Then you called me to get you out of it.
事后还让我做你的帮凶啊  操
That makes me an accessory after the fact, motherfucker.
我会讲清楚的  我怎么说你报告就怎么写
I'll tell you the facts, man. just write the report the way I say it happened,
到时候  神不知  鬼不觉
And then that's the way it is, and that's how it will be.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
听你的话把100万交公  现在成了瘟神
I'm a leper because I listened to you and turned in a million bucks.
自那以后没人愿意和我搭档
No one will work with me after that.
我可以洗脱罪名的  瑞奇  很简单
I can get off this shit, richie. that's easy.
全部取决于你的报告
Just write the report
我们是搭档  不要告发我啊
Between us, as partners.
我绝不能这么做
I can't do that.
嘿
Hey!
停车  停车
Stop! stop!
操你妈
Fuck it.
把后备箱打开
Open the trunk.
和平  和平  我们要和平
Peace now! peace now! peace now!
撤兵  撤兵  撤出越南
Get out, get out, get out of vietnam!
我们在竭力呼喊  停止越战
As loud as we can that the vietnam war should stop,
对美国来说停止战争
And that the best way to stop it is for the united states
最好的办法就是马上撤兵
To simply pack up and get out of vietnam right now.
怎么样?
How we looking?
常见的纯度基本上在25%到40%之间
Typically, what I see is 25%% to 45%% pure.
我的意思是  它不含杂质  生物碱和稀释剂
I mean, there's no adulterants, no alkaloids, no dilutants.
纯度百分之一百
It's 100%% .
我可以拿走了吗
May I?
你带走好了
Take it with you.
谢谢  弗兰克
Thank you, frank.
我买了  不用贷款  什么都不用
I'll take it. no contingencies, no loans, no nothing.
用现金
Cash.
太好了
Fabulous.
不想谈你的那些癖好  瑞奇  这些我太了解了
I'm not talking about your proclivities, richie. those I only know too well.
我想说的是你是个怎样的警察
I'm talking about being a cop.
你想说受贿吗
You're talking about taking money?
我不会那么做的  这不符合我的原则
I don't do that. it's not my thing.
那你和邻里的朋友关系怎么样?
What about your friends from the neighborhood?
-你还会和他们一起出去玩吗  -是的
Do you still hang out with them? yeah.
周末还会一起玩棒球
Play baseball on the weekends.
那些自作聪明的家伙?  真搞笑
Wise guys? that's gonna look good.
是和我高中的校友一起  那又怎么样?
Guys I went to high school with. so what?
那约瑟夫·索达诺呢?
What about joseph sodano?
他怎么啦?
What about him?
瑞奇  我正试图弄懂你妻子的话
Richie, I'm just trying to understand things your wife has said.
如果它们与事实不尽相符  请告诉我
If they're not true, tell me.
是的  他是其中的一个
Yeah, he's one of them.
-他也是你儿子的教父?  -是的
Is he also your son's godfather? yeah.
他肯定会和她上床的
He's definitely fucking her.
你真的很在意这个  还是你想让她不好过?
Do you really care about this? or do you just not want her to win ever?
二楼有个会见室  我们去那里吧
You know, there's an interview room on the second floor.
-正合我意  -门只有从里面才能锁起来
That's what I thought. the door only locks from the inside.
全体起立
All rise.
噢  噢  瑞奇  操我  粗暴点
Oh, god, richie. richie, fuck me like a cop, not a lawyer!
别接电话
Don't answer it!
喂?
Yeah?
-瑞奇·罗伯特  -嘿  是诺曼吗
Richie roberts. hey, norm?
你好  瑞奇·罗伯特
Hey. richie roberts.
你好  诺曼·莱利警官
Hi. detective norman reily.
-诺曼  你好吗  -很好
Hey, norm. how are you? good.
-是他吗  -是的
So, is that him? yeah.
-今晚可真不是时候  对吧?  -这里好像地铁站
Picked a nice night to come out, huh? it's like grand central around here.
一直都这样
It's been like this.
午夜能回家就够幸运了  这个我们以前从没见过
I'm lucky if I get home by midnight. it's like nothing we've seen before.
我得签字吗
Something I gotta sign?
嗯  这里
Yeah. it's right here.
这个我拿走了  我会向伊塞克斯县登记的  行不?
I'm taking this with me. I'll register it with essex county, all right?
成
All right.
在美国民众的首号敌人是滥用毒品
America's public enemy number one in the united states is drug abuse.
为了痛击并最终打败这个敌人
In order to fight and defeat this enemy,
必要发动全民攻势
It is necessary to wage a new, all-out offensive.
联邦政府已经宣布
Federal authorities have announced their intention
打算建立专门麻醉药管理局
To establish special narcotics bureaus
在华盛顿  纽约  洛杉矶  芝加哥...
In washington, new york, los angeles, chicago...
一名警官如果没有同伴的支援
A detective without the support of his fellow detectives
真的什么事都做不了
Really can't do much.
你知道我为什么没有同伴的原因
You know why I don't have it.
没事的  你做了你该做的
Doesn't matter. you did what you had to do.
世界上最伟大的城市现在比老鼠窝还乱
Greatest city in the world! and it's turning into an open sewer.
小偷小摸  毒品交易盛行
Everybody's stealing, dealing.
就像你  做了凭良心做事却落得个这样下场
Look at you. you can't work because you did your job.
欣慰的是  还有很多像你这样诚实的警察
Good news is, you're not the only honest cop in town.
华盛顿的特殊麻醉药管理局可不是走过场的
The special narcotics bureau in washington is not a dog and pony show.
他们是动真格的  因为他们还叫我们参与
They are sincere. I know this because they want us to orchestrate it.
我们这边我要你来牵头
And I want you to head up things here on our end.
如果是联邦政府  我对谁报告  邮局?
If it's federal, who do I answer to, the post office?
你对我报告就行了
No, you answer to me,
我还有美国联邦检控官  其他没了
Me and the us attorney, nobody else.
你以后再也不要踏进警所半步了
You never step foot in a police station again.
你自己找个场所  再挑几个人
You work out of your own place, you pick your own guys,
你得找几个绝对可靠的人
Guys that you know would not take a nickel off the sidewalk.
好了  那边有个漂亮的过道
Well, we got the lovely transit.
六百年历史的红木门
600-year-old mahogany doors.
你看看  你感受到了吧
Now, look at that. can't you just feel it?
我认为很棒
I think it's lovely.
小心
Watch your step.
看看这些华丽的地板
Look at these beautiful floors.
我不确定  至少也有两百年历史了
At least, I don't know, 200 years old.
怎么都不会开裂
And it's hard to get the cracks...
啊  这是我最喜欢的一个房间了
Now this was one of my favorite rooms
但是下水道有些问题
But we had some problems with the plumbing.
不过我修理好了  现在可以了
I even fixed it. I know it works.
不会漏水了
It's not gonna leak.
就这了
Here it is.
你有所不知  我小时候
You know, I used to be a really good
钢琴弹得很好的
Piano player when I was a kid,
但是后来荒废了
But then, I don't know why I forgot.
生活还得继续啊
Life goes on. well...
你还得看多久呢
How long are you gonna be?
噢  拜托
Oh, and do me a favor, please.
关好这些门
Mind the doors.
那些华丽的玻璃门都很经典
Those are beautiful, ornate glass doors, you know.
再来一次  吉米  加油
Here we go, jimmy. come on.
好的  投过来
Oh, yeah. give it back.
嘿
Huey's.
嘿  小子  你在做什么
Huey. what up, boy?
你是?
Yeah, who this?
你说呢  你以为是谁
Who you think it is, boy?
-弗兰克  -哪个弗兰克
Frank. frank who?
-你的兄弟弗兰克  黑鬼  -是你?
Frank your brother, negro. frankie?
对啦
That's right.
梅尔文  老妈在哪里?
Hey, melvin! melvin, where's ma?
-什么?  -弗兰克的电话
What? frank's on the phone!
-妈妈  -弗兰克  你过得不错吧
Hey, ma! how are you doing, frankie?
弗兰克打电话来了
Frank's on the phone!
-什么  -弗兰克打电话来了
Say what? mama, frank's on the phone!
弗兰克?  噢  感谢上帝
Frank? oh, my lord!
-什么时候?   -啊  你不会只是说说而已吧
Yeah, when? well, you just say it, man, yeah.
我六点钟再打
Listen, I'm gonna call y'all back
我要你把每个人都叫过来  懂了吗?
At 6:00. I want you to get everybody together, all right? get mama, get everybody.
-好的  -那先这样
All right? okay.
嘿  弗兰克!
Hey, frank!
怎么突然想家了啊  弗兰克?
What's happening, frank?
-嘿  弗兰克!  -过得不错吧  弗兰克叔叔
Hey, frankie. how you doing, uncle frank?
下车  让孩子们都下车
Get out the car. get the kids, get the kids.
瞧我的宝贝
Look at this, baby.
噢  上帝啊  见到你真是太高兴了  孩子
Oh, my lord! I'm so glad to see you, boy.
这块地可真够大的!  地方也很漂亮
Oh, I'm telling you, this is some piece of land you got here!
我们这些穷人来这儿干嘛呀?
I wonder what the poor people are doing here?
弗兰克  那房子是谁的?
And whose house is that, frankie?
妈妈  是你的
That is your house, mama.
-我的?  -是的
Mine? that's yours.
还能是谁的呢?
And who else?
过来  我的房间在那里  就那里
Now, there, that's my room right there, man. right over there.
还要来点甘蓝吗?
Anybody want some more collard greens?
看到所有的孩子和孙子坐在一起用餐
I wanna tell you how happy I am to see all my children at the table
我甭提多开心了
And the grandchildren at the same time.
-真是太开心了  你们多吃点
My heart's so happy. enjoy yourselves.
在吃着呢  奶奶
Right on, grandma.
瞧你真能吃  我希望你能找份工作  孩子
I hope you got a job, boy, the way you're eating over here.
那边的那个男孩  他的手臂真适合打棒球
That boy right there, he got a arm on him. I mean, a major league arm.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
难道不是吗
Ain't that right?
继续啊  爸
Right on, pop.
晚餐后  让你他露两手啊
Well, we'll see after dinner. we'll see him throw it around a little bit.
还是不要啦  你抓不到他的球的
No, no, you can't catch him, man.
我是说  我是说
I'm talking about... I'm talking about...
这小子投的球比吉布森的还势大力沉
This guy throw harder than gibson.
球速高达每小时95英里
We're talking 95 miles an hour.
-你能抓得住?  -他会...
Can you catch him? he gonna...
他只会抓到小草
He gonna catch the ground.
我记得我五岁的时候  我们好像一起玩过
We might've played catch, I think, when I was about five years old.
从那时起  他就一直玩不过我们了
Since then, he ain't been able to keep up.
这是你的房间  太完美了
This is your room. it's perfect.
啊
Oh. why, it's...
你看看这里
Will you look at this?
噢
Oh!
真是太完美了
Oh, it's beautiful. it's beautiful. it's just...
我
I...
怎么会有这个
How did you...
我请人做的
I had it made.
凭记忆
From memory.
-他们搬走它的时候你才五岁  -是的
You were five when they took it away on me. that's right.
你怎么还记得啊
How could you remember it?
我怎么会玩得了呢  妈妈
How could I forget, mama?
我正想说  太完美了
I'll just tell you it is perfect.
一切都太完美了
It's all perfect.
我很爱你  孩子
I can't tell you how much I love you.
我也爱你  妈妈
I love you, too, mama.
真是太好了
It's okay.
这两个家伙  特擅长于窃听
Both these guys, good with wires,
他们有可靠的线人
They got solid informants,
他们都诚实而又勇敢
And they're honest and they're fearless.
他们都和你一样  瑞奇  都疯了
They're insane, richie, like you.
他们在哪
Where are they?
和那边高挑的女孩子在跳舞的是琼斯
That's jones with the skinny white broad.
基层警员中最棒的的
Best I ever seen on the street.
他了解毒品交易  但从来不碰那玩意儿
He knows dope, but he's together, all right?
伟人非常正直
He's a stand-up guy all round.
和那两个肥胖的黑女人在一起的是阿布鲁佐
And that's abruzzo with the two fat black ones.
他喜欢屁股大的女人
He loves a big ass, man.
像头蛮牛  还好不会胡闹  只是有点脾气
He's a bulldog. he don't fuck around, all right. he's got a bit of a temper,
他是绝对可靠的一个人
Yeah, but you can trust this guy with your grandmother.
瑞奇 我们合作
Listen, richie. we work together.
如果你要我加盟  你得把他们也带上
You want me, you gotta take them, too.
我们什么时候开始
When do we start?
我的老板拥有纽约最大的公司之一
The man I worked for, he had one of the biggest companies in new york city.
这家公司他都经营50多年了
He ran it for more than 50 years.
我跟他有十五年八个月九天了
Fifteen years, eight months and nine days,
我每天都待他边上  我替他卖命
I was with him every day. I worked for him,
我保护他  照顾他  也从他那学到了好多东西
I protected him, I looked after him, I learned from him.
邦比很有钱  但是他不像白人那样有钱
Bumpy was rich, but he wasn't white man rich, you see?
他没什么财产
He wasn't wealthy.
他没有自己的公司  虽然他认为他有
He didn't own his own company. he thought he did, but he didn't,
只是由他经营
He just managed it.
公司是白人的  可以说他是替白人打工
The white man owned it, so they owned him.
-不过我不受制于任何人的  -嘿
Nobody owns me, though. hey.
-宝贝  你好吗  -很好
How you doing, babe? good.
那是因为我有自己的公司  我出售自己的产品
That's 'cause I own my own company, and my company sells a product
这个没有竞争
That's better than the competition,
比竞争的代价要低
At a price that's lower than the competition.
我们在这卖什么  弗兰克?
Well, what are we selling here, frank?
你好吗  雷德?
How you doing, red?
这是我的兄弟  他们刚从北卡罗来纳来
These are my brothers, just got here from north carolina.
兄弟们  她叫雷托
Everybody, this is redtop.
你好吗
Hello. how you doing?
-女士们  -你好
And the ladies. hey.
怎么了?  没见过女人的裸体吗?
What wrong? y'all niggas ain't never seen hoochie before?
为什么他们都赤身裸体的?
Why are they all naked?
这样她们就偷不了东西
So they can't steal nothing.
噢  那倒是
Oh, right.
生意上最可贵的品质是  诚实  正直  勤奋
The most important thing in business is honesty, integrity, hard work,
家庭
Family,
永远都不能忘记我们的出身
Never forgetting where we came from.
谢谢  查琳
Thank you, charlene.
你就是你
See, you are what you are in this world,
不可能是其他的
That's either one of two things.
要么作大人物
Either you're somebody,
要么是小人物  我马上回来
Or you're nobody. be right back.
我马上就要  要是让我回来再找你的话
I need these fresh. cause if I have to come back here and get you,
-你会吃不了兜着走的  -谭哥
You know what it is. tango.
-不要当我在开玩笑  -是  先生  我听见了
Don't y'all play that. vendor 1: yes, sir, I hear you.
你就不用回来了  没这个必要了
You won't have to come back. there won't be no problem.
弗兰克 你要来点什么吗
Vendor 2: what about you, frank? you need anything?
我的钱呢  雷托已经把包裹给你了
Where's my money? redtop gave you the package.
你本来该把钱送过来给我的
You're supposed to be handing me my money.
这里有一个罐子  你得分百分之二十给我
Here's a jar right here. twenty percent.
-你也有一个罐子  -没错
Oh, you got the jar? that's right.
把这够娘养的赶走  噢  你要干嘛
Get the fuck out of here... oh! what you gonna do?
你想怎么样  弗兰克?  你要干嘛
What the fuck you gonna do, frank? huh? what you doing?
你要在这么多人面前杀我  开枪吧  来啊
You gonna shoot me in front of everybody? huh? come on.
操
Shit.
这是你的百分之二十
There you go. twenty percent.
我刚刚说到哪了
So, what was I saying?
琼斯
Jones.
Jonesy.
弹得不错啊  伙计
That was nice, man.
我只不过在发挥我的音乐天赋而已
Just doing my melodious thing, baby.
我知道
Got you.
这就是伊塞克斯县新成立的反麻醉品特别行动小组
This is the newly formed essex county narcotics squad.
我们的目标是捉到大鱼  不是街头小混混
Our mandate is to make major arrests. no street guys.
我们要找出供应商和经销商
We're looking for the suppliers and the distributors.
海洛因  可卡因  安非他命  大麻1000磅以上
Heroin, cocaine, amphetamines. no grass under 1,000 pounds.
粉剂毒品40千克以上才是我们的目标
No powder under 40 kilograms.
少于这些的  都由其他人来管
Any less than that, then somebody else can waste their time.
我们处理的是大宗的货物  大笔的钱  巨大的诱惑
We gonna be handling the big shipments, the big money and the big temptation.
我听过你事迹
I heard a story about you.
你发现了100万没有做过标记现金
That you found a million dollars in unmarked cash
然后交公了  真有这回事吗
And gave that shit back. is that true?
是的  你们有什么不爽吗
Yeah, I did. anybody got a problem with that?
其实我也不爽  我每天都在后悔
So do i, you know? I think about it every day.
不然现在我应该在佛罗里达坐着68英尺长的游艇钓鱼了
I should be down in south florida with a 68-foot cruiser doing fishing charters.
是我们两个人一起
You and me, both.
但是  我没有  所以现在我在这
But you know, I didn't, so here I am,
和你们一起追捕一些其它种类的鲨鱼(毒贩)
And we'll be looking to land other kind of sharks.
-准备好了吗  -没问题
All right? bingo.
-瑞奇  看到没  -恩
See that, richie? yeah.
这些是以前市场上卖的货
And this stuff is your everyday stuff.
这个蓝色魔法强度是普通货色的两倍
But this blue magic, twice the potency.
这是我见过纯度最高的
I mean, it's the purest thing
直接吸食都可以了
I ever seen in the streets. it's strong enough to smoke.
适合那些怕针头的城郊白人小孩
And that's for those white suburban kids who are scared of needles.
我只花了10块
I paid 10 bucks for that.
而且它到处都有  每个角落都有
And it's everywhere. I mean, it's on every corner out there.
这怎么可能
So, how is that possible?
谁会把好一倍的毒品用一半的价格卖出呢
Who can afford to sell shit twice as good for half as much?
弗兰克  见到你太好了
Hey, man. frankie, baby, good to see you!
最近怎么样
Everything's good?
刚从欧洲回来
Yeah, man, just got back from europe,
在法国南部呆了2个月呢
Over there for two months, south of france, man.
看这里  这里  很好
Photographer 1: look right, look right. wonderful, wonderful.
尼克
Photographer 2: nicky!
尼克  笑一个
Photographer 3: give us a smile, nicky.
把封面露出来
Photographer 4: show us the cover.
知道什么意思吗
You know what I'm saying, man?
尼克  这里
Photographer 5: hey, nicky, over here.
拿去吧
There you go.
尼克
Nicky!
看看这是谁啊
Who is that? look at you, my man.
不错啊
All right.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
黑色轰炸机  永远的冠军
The brown bomber! the champ!
乔·路易斯先生
Mr. joe louis!
跟乔一起的是谁啊
Who's that with joe?
波多黎各小姐
Miss puerto rico.
-波多黎各?  -恩
Puerto rico? mmm-hmm.
她是选美皇后吗
Is she a beauty queen?
那当然  货真价实
For real. the beauty queen.
欢迎  欢迎  我的好兄弟
Welcome. my main man. my main man.
你们能不能都出去一下
Can you all excuse us for a minute, please?
没问题  弗兰克
Yeah, sure, frank.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了
What's going on?
-你笑什么  -我不知道
What you smiling about? I don't know.
-这是在干嘛   -什么干嘛
What is this? huh? what's what?
-什么干嘛  -过来
What's what? come here.
你穿的这是什么
What is that you got on?
什么什么
What's what, man?
就是这个  你穿的是什么
Yeah, that! what you got on.
非常非常非常好的西装啊
This is a very, very, very nice suit.
非常非常非常好的西装?  这就是件小丑服
That's a very, very, very nice suit, huh? that's a clown suit. that's a costume...
这衣服上就象写着"逮捕我"三个字
That says "arrest me."
你懂吗?  你太招摇了
You understand? you're too loud.
太显眼了  看着我
You're making too much noise. look at me.
最显眼的那个一定是最弱的  我告诉过你的
The loudest one in the room is the weakest one in the room. I told you that.
懂了没?  你现在在学尼克·巴恩斯吗?
All right? what, are you trying to be like nicky barnes, now?
你对尼克有什么不爽的吗?  我喜欢尼克
What's your problem with nicky, man? I like nicky.
我没对他有什么不爽  你喜欢尼克对吧?
I ain't got no problem with nicky. oh, you like nicky?
-是啊  -所以你想跟尼克一样?
Yeah! you want to be like nicky?
你想变成超级大苍蝇?  你想为他工作?
You want to be superfly? you wanna work for him?
跟他一起坐牢?  帮他煮饭?
Share a jail cell with him? maybe cook for him?
他想跟你谈谈
He wants to talk to you.
你跟他说我的事啦?  你想干什么?
Oh, so now you talking to him about me? what? you...
-跟他什么说了?  -不是这样的
About what? what is it about? it ain't like that.
-那是怎样的?  -我们聊天的时候
Then what is it like? we were talking,
-聊到了你  -我什么?
Your name came up. about what?
我不知道  我就告诉他我会跟你说的
I don't know, man. I told him I'd tell you.
你知道吗  你...
You know... boy, you...
如果你不是我弟弟  我会杀了你  你知道吧
You know, if you wasn't my brother, I'd kill you. you know that, don't you?
我他妈会打爆你的头
I'd blow your motherfucking brains out.
别这样
Come on, man. don't be like that.
这星期我就带你去买衣服
I'm taking you shopping this week.
-我已经买了衣服了  -我看出来了
I went shopping. I can tell.
我看到你内心深处
See deep into you
我知道你现在在想什么
And know what you're thinking now
如果我正是你所需要的
And if I'm what you're needing
我需要一点暗示
I need some kind of sign
让我知道  因为你的心思我猜不透
Let me know, cause I can't read your mind
你是否也和我一样  还是我一个人在单相思
Are you in or am I in this on my own?
我需要从你那得到一些线索
I need some clue from you
就是点税务上的问题
It's a tax thing.
我的律师正处理呢
It's a mistake my lawyers are straightening out,
不过现在...
But for the time being...
乔  你欠了多少
How much do you owe, joe?
没多少  就...
It's nothing. it's like...
五万
Fifty grand.
没问题
You got it.
谢谢你
Thank you, man.
我有钱马上还...
Hey, I'm gonna pay you back as soon as i...
乔  这不是借的  是我送你的
Joe, this ain't no loan. it's a gift. all right?
你为邦比做了那么多  我们欠你的
All you did for bumpy, we owe you.
昂起头来  骄傲的活下去好吗?
Keep your chin up. all right? okay?
你现在不过是陷入低迷而已
All you have which is down there. down.
情绪有点低落
Chin down.
先走一步了  回头见啦
All right. doc, will see you, okay?
你还欠我支舞  对吗
You still owe me that dance, right?
快点拉
Doc, come on.
弗兰克  看看那边
Frank, check this.
-你好  -你好
How you doing? hi.
弗兰克·卢卡斯
Frank lucas.
伊娃·肯朵
Eva kendo.
很高兴认识你  伊娃
Nice to meet you, eva.
我也很高兴认识你  弗兰克
Nice to meet you, frank.
你是弗兰克  这是你的地盘?
You're frank and this is your place?
对  我是弗兰克  这是我的地盘
That's right. I'm frank and this is my place.
这为什么要叫"斯莫"呢?
Why is it called small's?
为什么不叫弗兰克夜总会
Why don't you call it frank's?
当你拥有一样东西时  想叫它什么就叫什么
When you own something, you can call it what you want.
斯莫夜总会
Small's.
弗兰克夜总会  或者弗兰克斯莫夜总会
Or frank's. frankie small's.
或者叫斯莫弗兰克夜总会
Small's frankie.
没错
That's right.
你准备把我手放开吗
You want to let my hand go?
好
Okay.
你要走了吗
You leaving?
没  我只是回到我那桌去
No, I was going to my table.
哦  要不要人陪你去
Okay. need somebody to go with you?
-要?  -恩
Yes? mmm-hmm.
这么多的头面人物
All the cheesies.
在这  对  这是谁?
Right here, here we go. what have we got here?
洗手了没?
Wash your hands?
我只有一张  别弄脏了
I got one print of that, don't smudge it.
对  就这样
Yeah. there you go.
老大  他呢  他是谁?
Hey, spearman, what about him? who is that?
乔伊·索达诺  道恩·卡塔诺的外甥
Joey sodano. don cattano's nephew.
是啊  是啊  把他放在那  大人物的旁边
Yeah, yeah. put him up there by the big man.
他看起来像你叔叔  阿布鲁佐
He looks like your uncle, abruzzo.
是啊  不过他可没我叔叔帅
Yeah, but he's not as handsome.
-他看起来更像你姐姐  -"冰锥"的照片哪去了
He looks more like your sister. where's ice pick's mug?
是啊  真幽默啊你们
Yeah, that's funny.
在外头办事的时候你们也能这么幽默就好了
Maybe you guys should take that show on the road.
我们要找"冰锥"保罗
So we need ice pick paul.
-冰锥保罗?  -对
Ice pick paul? yeah.
在这呢  放上去
There you go. get him up.
冰锥保罗  他的地位可不低  得放到顶上去
Ice pick paul, he goes way up there, up top.
冰锥保罗只是个小兵  这位是上尉呢
No, ice pick paul, he's a fucking soldier. this guy's a lieutenant.
这怎么可能呢
How's that even fucking possible?
那是本尼"主教"
That's benny the bishop.
那是个小兵  这是上尉  小兵怎么可能在上面
That guy is a soldier. this guy's a lieutenant. no way that guy's on top.
你还在想本尼主教
You thinking of benny the bishop.
"双袜"温尼是那混蛋卡塔诺的女婿
Vinnie two socks is fucking cattano's deadbeat son-in-law.
琼斯说的没错
Jonesy's right.
你们谁真的见过冰锥保罗卖毒品?
Hey, which one of you guys has ever actually seen ice pick paul selling drugs?
亲眼看见他的生意一落千丈?
Actually seen it go down?
对  看见他的生意一落千丈
Yeah, seen it go down.
在他地盘  亲眼看到他处理毒品
Been in his place. seen him handle drugs.
那个线人跟我们说的...
That rat, ricky, has told us...
可惜那家伙4个星期前已经死翘翘了
He's fucking dead. about four weeks ago.
他死了
He's dead.
那  这样的话
All right, well,
我们就能把他从这板上取下来了
We can take him off the fucking board.
这板上的任何一个我们都没有确实的证据
I don't think we got any solid evidence on anybody on that board.
瑞奇  你什么意思
What you saying, richie?
这是我们好几星期的努力成果呢
This is weeks and weeks of work, man.
我的意思是  把它取下来
I'm saying, take it down.
我们得从街上重新开始
We got to start again from the street.
你好  哪位
Hi, who's this?
你好  盖博?  我是斯哥特啊
Hello? gabe? yeah, it's scott. yeah.
斯哥特  最近怎么样啊  兄弟
Scotty! what's going down, brother?
你昨晚给我的雪地轮胎
Those snow tires you gave me last night.
进了新货没?
They come in yet?
哦  雪地轮胎啊?
Oh, the snow tires?
是啊  我还想要买
Yeah. I want some more of them.
再给我1个半
Give me one-and-a-half
1个半
One-and-a-half,
这单子挺大啊
That's a pretty big order.
对  我要又大又白的雪地轮胎
Yeah, I want the big whitewalls,
他们最好能驶上十万英里
They better get at least 100,000 miles.
好  这样吧
All right, I'll tell you what.
你明天上午来
You come in here tomorrow morning
我帮你装好轮胎
I'm gonna set you up real nice
再给你些雪地轮胎特惠  好不好
With a whitewall special, all right?
谢拉  兄弟
Thanks, bro.
没问题
No problem.
这可比你一年的工资还多啊  瑞奇
That's considerably more than one year's salary, richie.
如果这钱没了  我也没法再给你弄了
If it disappears, I will not be able to get it for you again.
这是你的了
That's yours.
为了这2万小钱  我得把命押上
Signing my life away again, for a lousy twenty grand.
货是蓝色魔法吧?
It has to be blue magic, right?
是是  肯定是蓝色
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, it's gonna be blue.
明天你就能来拿了
You can pick it up here tomorrow.
2万块
$20,000.
就放那吧
Just leave it there.
-怎么样  -还行
How'd you do? good.
他来了
Here he comes.
-那就是他了?  -恩
That's him? yep.
还真快
That was quick.
瑞奇  如果他进城了我们怎么办
Richie, if he goes in the city, what do we fucking do?
跟着那钱  我们还能怎么办
Stay with the fucking money, that's what we do.
我们跟着钱  行吧?
We stay with the money, all right?
我们不能进城啊
We can't go in the fucking city.
不能也得能  2万块在那呢
Yes, we can. that's 20 grand in there, all right,
我对那钱要负责任  不能弄丢了
That I'm responsible for. I ain't losing it.
但那超出了我们的管辖区
It's out of our jurisdiction!
-他妈的你给我跟着钱  -好吧  好吧
Follow the money! all right, all right, all right!
他停下了
He's pulling over.
好  我们得行动了
All right, here we go.
让我在这下吧
Let me out here.
你可别走掉啊
Don't disappear, all right?
我就在这绕圈子
I'll circle the block.
开啊
Move!
你他妈谁啊  操  赶紧开走啊
Hey! who's the fuck? you gotta fucking move!
警察  我在追捕犯人
Police officer. I'm commandeering
需要征用你的车  从车里出来
Your vehicle. get out of the car.
谁他妈管你啊  这是纽约
Who the fuck cares about you? this is new york city, man.
去抢别人的车吧
Get someone else's car!
从车里出来
Get out of the car.
我们就不能和平共处吗
Come on, man. can't we live in peace...
弗兰克  坐下
Frankie, frankie! sit down.
干嘛
Man 1: what?
生日快乐  先生们  最近怎么样
Happy birthday, gentlemen. how you doing, huh?
他准备要干嘛?  要去打保龄?
He's about to do something, huh? he's going bowling?
看看  一击全中
Look at that. strike.
你腿中间是啥玩意  袋子里是什么
Hey, what's between your legs? what's in the bag?
-没什么  -起来  你丫的给我起来
Nothing. get up, you fucker. get the fuck up!
别这样
Man 2: knock it off.
闭上嘴  我他妈跟你说什么了
Man 3: shut the fuck up! what did I tell you?
把你头给我低下
Man 4: keep your fucking head down.
闭嘴  这是谁的袋子
Man 3: shut up! whose bag is this?
-你们要干嘛?  -给我闭嘴  坐下
What're you doing? man 3: sit down and shut up!
你可别给我动
Man 4: don't you move!
喂  先生们
Hey, guys? guys! officers!
我是瑞奇  从诺瓦克来的
Hey, I'm richie roberts, from newark.
这是我的钱
That's my money.
什么鬼东西  什么钱
What the fuck? what money, huh? what money?
那些钱有序号的 对不对？
The bills are sequenced, right?
他们被依塞克斯县法院注册过了  看看吧
They're registered with the essex county prosecutor's office. just check them out.
他们都是以CF3500开头的  看看
They all start with cf3500. have a look.
狗日的  居然是注册过的
Fucking registers.
我还以为这次下来足够我买辆新车了
I thought I had a fucking chris-craft sitting in my driveway.
是我疏忽  把钱还给我吧
Honest mistake. I'll just get the money.
-这一次放过你  -恩
This time. all right.
-给你  -好  谢谢
There it is. all right. thank you.
我想想  我最后一次去新泽西是什么时候
When was the last time I was in jersey? let me think.
我从没去过那
Never.
你没打声招呼就来这干嘛
What're you doing, coming over here unannounced?
你以为我们不会把你怎么样吗?
You don't think you could get hurt doing that?
你拿到你的钱了  瑞奇
You got your fucking money, richie.
再也别不打声招呼就擅自来这里了
And never, ever come into this city again unannounced.
你就算来这看场歌剧
You come in to see a fucking broadway show,
也得跟我打声招呼先  看我答不答应
You call ahead first, see if it's okay with me.
没问题
No problem. all right.
走了  打球去了
Let's go, hit some balls.
衣服不错啊
Great suits, pal.
这是你的车吗
Is that your car?
这车真他妈不错
That's a fucking great car.
回新泽西的路上小心点
Have a nice fucking trip back to jersey.
恩
All right.
快点  我还得喝茶去呢  走了
Come on, I got a tee time. let's go.
你到那干嘛呢
What were you doin' there?
货是从那边出来的
Well, that's where this dope is coming from.
蓝色魔法  是从纽约出来的
Blue magic, it's coming out of new york.
你觉得我该怎么做  不管它?
What do you expect me to do, ignore it?
出租车司机要告你故意伤害加偷窃
The cab driver has filed aggravated assault and grand theft charges
他也可能会撤诉
Which he may reconsider
不过这要看新泽西州政府给他多少钱私了
Depending on how much the state of new jersey offers to settle.
我给他看了我的证明  我告诉他我是警察了
I showed him my id. I told him I was a cop.
你偷了他的车还把他打晕了
You stole his cab and you knock him out.
我在追那2万块  好不好
I was chasing the 20 grand, all right?
下次  给他看勋章之前先把他打晕了
Next time, knock him out before you show him your badge.
听着  我不想再听到你去纽约了
Look, I don't want to hear about you going into new york again.
那这案子就可以结束了
Well, then this investigation's over.
你没听懂我的话
You're not listening to me.
我说的是  "我不想再听到你去纽约了"
I said, "i don't want to hear about you going into new york again."
你想干嘛就干嘛
You do whatever you have to do.
想去哪就去哪
You go wherever you have to go
查出是谁把毒品带到这国家来的
To figure out who's bringing this shit into the country.
但是不要让我听到
Just don't tell me about it.
那是你马子  就在那
There's your girl, right there.
-嘿  -你好
Hey, how'd you do? hi.
-我没让你等太久吧  -没
I didn't keep you waiting long, did i? no. fine.
那就好  你这么美丽的女人不应该为
Good. a woman as beautiful as you shouldn't have to wait.
任何东西等待的
For anything.
谢谢你  女士  你还是和从前一样漂亮
Thank you, ma'am. you as pretty as ever.
嘿  先生
Hey, doc.
汤米
Tommy!
听说你儿子上周橄榄球赛两次触地得分哦
Heard your boy scored two touchdowns last week.
是啊  我为他骄傲
Sure. sure do make father proud.
恩  不错
All right.
这是你父亲?
This is your father?
这是马丁·路德·金(黑人民权运动领袖)
That's martin luther king.
-才不是呢  -是的 是马丁·路德·金
It is not. it is. it is martin luther king.
你知道吧  "我有个梦想"
You know, "i have a dream"?
当然
Of course.
那不是他  那是...
No, that's...
对我来说  他就跟马丁·路德·金一样重要
He was just as important as martin luther king to me.
他做什么了
What did he do?
做了很多事情  他是个很好的朋友
A lot of things. he was a friend
他为纽约服务  纽约也为他服务
And served new york. new york served him.
他是我老板
He was my boss.
也是我老师
My teacher.
他教你什么了
What did he teach you?
他教了我很多
He taught me a lot of things. he
他教会了我怎么利用时间
Taught me how to take my time.
教了做任何事都得用心  用爱
Taught me that if I was going to do something, to do it with care, with love.
还有什么吗?
Anything else?
他教了我怎么当个绅士
He taught me to be a gentleman.
所以你是个绅士啰?
That's what you are?
我正在努力  过来
That's what I try to be. come here.
来这  坐这
Come here. sit right here.
看着我
Look at me.
我在曼哈顿拥有5座公寓
I own about five apartments in manhattan.
我东岸有无数个家
Homes all over the east coast,
我没有带你去任何一个
I could have taken you to any one of them, but I didn't.
-我把你带到了这里  -弗兰克
I brought you here. frank,
我正找你呢
I was looking for you, boy.
因为我想让你见见我妈妈
Because I wanted you to meet my mother.
妈妈  怎么样
How you doing, ma?
这是她吗
Is this her?
-伊娃  这是我妈妈  -你好  我是伊娃
Eva, this is my mother. hi, eva.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
-她太漂亮了  -是吧
She's beautiful! yeah?
弗兰克  看看她  她就像从天堂来的天使
Look at her, frank. she's an angel come down from heaven.
谢谢
Thank you.
罗伯特先生  我们预约过的
Mr. roberts? I'm here for our appointment.
-早上好  -早上好
Morning. morning.
对不起  我们有预约过?
Sorry. our appointment?
社区儿童服务机构
Child social services.
不过她有提你的名字
She did mention your name, though.
那空中小姐?
The stewardess?
不是  不是那空中小姐
No, not the stewardess.
那个儿童机构的女士  她提了你的名字
The lady from child services. she mentioned your name.
就在她问我有没有跟罪犯有任何联系之后
Right after she asked me if I associated with any criminals.
太好了  加油加油
Boy 1: all right, go! go, go!
你想看吗?
Boy 2: yeah! you wanna see this?
嘿  孩子们
Hey, boys.
乔伊  嘿  乔伊
Joey. hey, joey!
去游泳去  快去
Get in the pool. go on.
快点快点
Come on. come on.
她怎么知道我名字的
So, how'd she get my name?
-罗莉  -恩
Laurie. hmm.
她最近说了很多
She's been saying a lot lately.
很多很多
A lot.
你叫我当你儿子的教父的时候
You know, when you asked me to be your son's godfather,
我是很认真的
I took it very seriously.
我知道  我知道并很感激你
I know. I know and I appreciate that.
我跟你说好  我会负起责任的
And I said yes, I would take on this responsibility.
如果你出了什么事 会照顾你儿子
Take care of your son, if god forbid, something happened to you.
乔  她对儿童机构说的那些事
Joe, the kind of things she's saying to child social services
让我声誉上受到了很到影响
Made me look really bad, all right. you know,
半夜三更随时出门  周围都是人渣线人和女人
Out at all kinds of hours at night time, lowlife informants around, women.
有像我这样的老朋友
Old friends like me.
有像你这样的老朋友
Old friends like you, yeah.
乔叔叔  看着我
Uncle joey, watch me, okay?
我懂了
Okay, I understand.
我会告诉他们你想要我说的  我会帮你撒谎
They ask me, I'll tell them what you want me to tell them. I'll lie for you.
别  别撒谎  你不用撒谎
No, don't lie. you don't have to lie.
就  忽略掉某些细节就行了
Just, omit certain details.
行
Sure. all right.
我还想问你件别的事
You know, there's something else I was gonna ask you.
别的事
Something else.
你也可以不回答
You don't have to answer if you don't want.
蓝色魔法  知道什么吗
Blue magic. anything?
只知道有很多人被这玩意儿逼得失业破产走投无路
Just a lot of sorrow, misery from guys getting put out of work, that's all.
什么  你的人?
What, your guys?
反正我知道有人
Just guys.
你知道那是从哪来的吗
You thinking about where it's coming from?
南方吧  我听说
Guys down south. that's all I heard.
-古巴吗?  -我不知道
Cubans? I don't know.
不是墨西哥
Not mexico.
我不知道
I don't know.
你是说  那是从南美洲来的吗?
You're telling me, it's coming in from south America?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只能说  不管是谁
All I can tell you is whoever it is,
他们都在扰乱市场秩序
they're upsetting the natural order of things.
我知道的也只有这么多了
And that's all there is.
怎么了
What's up?
兄弟  怎么样了
My man, how we looking?
弗兰克  这位是麦克·索博塔
Frank, I want you to meet mike sobota.
-你好  索博塔先生  -你好
How are you doing, mr. sobota? how are you?
有什么能为你效劳的吗
What can I get you?
那个左撇子怎么样了?  就是你侄子跟我说的那个
How about a left-hander? from what charlie tells me, your nephew.
-就是洋基队那个  -哦  洋基队  嗨  施蒂夫
Oh, this is the... yankees, yeah. hey, steve! yankees.
-施蒂夫  过来下  -失陪一下
Steve! come here. excuse me one second.
这孩子很不错  你得帮我把他带进洋基队去
This boy's good, okay? I want you to put him on the yankees.
你很棒不是吗
Cause you good enough, ain't you?
我叫卢卡斯  哪怕是最差的时候我也很棒  杰克
I'm a lucas. good enough on a bad day, jack.
他是很棒  但还是得努力
He's good enough on a bad day, so don't make it a bad day,
做事就要做的漂亮点  明白吗?
Make it a good day, you understand?
纽约警察  退后  退后 都老实点
Nypd, excuse me, police department. back up, baby.
吉米  你给我老实点  明白吗
Taking your ass in, jimmy. uh-uh.
-放老实点  -警察怎么连个手铐都没有
Taking your ass in. where are the handcuffs?
我有执照的
I got a license for that, motherfucker.
你有吸毒的执照吗?  让让好吗
You got a license for this? excuse me, all right?
妈的
Shit. all right! yeah!
你知道吗  我得逮捕你
Now, you know what? I gotta arrest you for that shit.
这些在街上可都是抢手货啊
That shit's too good to be on the street.
等等  试试这个  你会改变主意的
Wait a minute, I got this for you. you ain't got to arrest nobody.
你在贿赂我吗
Are you bribing me now?
我告诉你  我今天要逮捕每一个人
I'll tell you what, I'm arresting everybody!
每一个人知道吗!  就他妈先拿你开刀
Now, all you're under arrest! you first!
这是我家人  那是
That's my family. that's my...
借过  借过
Excuse me, excuse me.
真不错  宝贝
Back it up, baby.
那是什么鬼东西
What was that?
伙计  你他妈怎么了
Come on, guys. what's the matter with you, man?
我再问一次  那是什么鬼东西
I said, what the hell was that? what was what?
-你究竟想干嘛  -冷静  哥们
I said what the hell are you doing, man? be cool, man!
你他妈到底怎么回事
What's your fucking problem?
你哪根筋不对了
What the hell's wrong with you?
我操
Goddamn!
他死不了  我只是射了他的腿而已
He's all right. I just shot him in the leg, is all.
操  吉米
Damn, jimmy!
你给我起来
Get up.
都出去  都他妈给我出去
All right, everybody, get out! get out!
算了  弗兰克  意外而已
Come on, frank, it was an accident.
-根本就不是什么意外  -他很后悔
It wasn't no goddamn accident. he feels terrible.
他才不会  你看看毒品把他搞成那个鬼样
He don't feel shit, 'cause he's coked up all the motherfucking time!
他是你司机  开除他
He's your driver. get rid of him.
嘿  哥们  那可是你的堂兄啊
Come on, man, that's your cousin!
管我鸟事
That ain't shit to me!
他?  对我来说什么都不是
He don't mean nothing to me.
那你让他怎么办?  回家种地吗
What's he gonna do, go back home?
我才不管他死活
I don't give a damn what he does!
就让他滚回家去种地吧
Send his ass home! hey! hey! hey!
不要擦它  你别把它弄脏了
Hey! don't rub on that! you blot that!
你知道吗  那他妈是羊绒毛的
You understand? that's alpaca!
25000美金的羊绒毛地毯就他妈被你弄成那样了
That's $25,000 alpaca! you blot that shit!
别他妈擦了  用苏打水洗掉吧
You don't rub it! put the club soda on there.
一群白痴
Simple simon-ass motherfuckers.
听着  从现在开始都别惹我
Listen, from now on, don't nobody talk to me directly! you understand?
有事情跟休伊说  然后休伊再来告诉我
You got business with me, you talk to huey! huey, you talk to me! you got it?
好吧
All right.
不要用电话  要当面说  明白吗
Damn it, never on the phone! you got it?
知道了  知道了
I got it. all right!
把他妈的太阳镜取下来
And take them goddamn sunglasses off.
Take the goddamn sunglasses off!
干嘛啊
Damn it, man.
一群白痴
Simple simon-ass motherfuckers.
这里整个地方都是进口的
The whole place was imported.
每一块砖都是
Brick by brick.
格罗切斯特郡
Gloucestershire.
-哪儿?  -英国
Who? great britain.
到你了
Yours.
准备好了
Here you go.
放靶！
Pull!
好了  伊娃
Come, eva.
来参观下这房子吧
I'm sure you're dying to see the rest of the house.
当然  失陪了
Of course. excuse me.
非常感谢你们的招待
Thank you for a wonderful lunch. it was delicious.
你怎么看垄断
What do you think of monopolies?
你怎么看
You mean like the game?
我觉得垄断不太好
No, I just think monopolies were made illegal in the country, frank,
那样就失去竞争了
Cause nobody wants to compete, you know.
没人愿意和一个垄断集团竞争
Nobody wants to compete, not with a monopoly.
如果你让那些牛奶农场去竞争
I mean, you let the dairy farmers do that,
第二天肯定会有一半人已经破产了了
Half of them would be out of business tomorrow.
没办法  都是为了讨生活
Just trying to make a living.
那是你的权利  我是说
That's your right, I mean,
人人都有权利去选择怎么生活  这就是美国
It's everyone's right. it's America.
我们只是不能太霸道了  得给别人留条活路
We just can't do it at the unreasonable expense of others.
不然就会变得不美国了
Cause then it becomes un-American.
这就是为什么一加仑牛奶的价格
That's why the price we pay for that gallon of milk
总是不会和它的实际生产成本一样
Could never represent the true cost of production
因为价格必须有人来制定和控制  这样才对大家都公平
Cause it's got to be controlled. it's gotta be set. it's gotta be fair.
有谁来控制?  我觉得自己定的价格就很公平
Gotta be controlled by who? I set a price that I think is fair.
-我不觉得那样公平  -你觉得不公平?
I don't think it's fair. you don't?
-我不觉得那样公平  -可我觉得公平
I don't think it's fair. I think it's fair.
我知道  消费者对你的货很满意
I mean, I know your customers are happy, frank,
但他们不过是群瘾君子而已
Bunch of fucking junkies that they are.
但你得也为那些挤奶工们想想  你为我们想过吗
But we fellow dairy farmers out here, frank, are you thinking of us?
你为他们考虑过吗
You thinking of them?
-挤奶工  -对
The dairy farmers? yeah.
多米尼克  他们也没为我着想过啊
I'm thinking of them, dominic, about as much as they've ever thought about me.
行  先不扯这个了
I'm just thinking out loud now.
如果你把一部分货拿出来
If you took some of your inventory, frank,
批发给其他人
And you sold it wholesale...
先坐
Sit.
我们能合作  我们来分销
We could work. we could do some distribution.
我不知道怎么合作  我现在就做得挺好的
I don't know. I'm pretty good, dominic.
我占有110街  155街  我足够了
You know, I got 110th, 155th, river to river. I'm all right.
我是说我们一起把它做大
That's kind of a mom and pop store next to what I'm talking about.
把它推向整个市场
I mean, let's go at least bigger than kmart.
洛杉矶  底特律  拉斯维加斯  把货推向全国市场
I'm talking about la, chicago, detroit, las vegas. let's go nationwide, huh?
我绝对保证你的安全  那不正是你想要的吗
I'm gonna guarantee you your peace of mind here. you don't want that?
你需要它
You're going to need it.
我不知道你怎么看我
I don't know how you view me, you know.
但我是个有修养的人  弗兰克
I'm kind of a renaissance man, frank.
我每天打交道的那些人
You know, the people I deal with on a daily basis,
甚至都不是文明人
You know, they're not enlightened, frank.
你跟他们说公民权如同对牛弹琴
You talk to them about civil rights, they don't know, you know.
而且他们不喜欢改变
They're not open to change.
总是按传统和老规矩办事  一直都是这样
Not from the way things are done and who's doing it.
但是如果我跟他们说一声就不会有什么误会
I talk to them, there's just no misunderstandings.
这就是我能给你提供的安全
And that's what I mean by your peace of mind.
你现在进货价格是多少?  七万五  八万美金一公斤?
You're paying, what, $75,000, $80,000 a kilo?
我也是个有内涵的人
I'm a renaissance man, too.
你买的话我只要五万美金一公斤
I'll consider $50,000.
干嘛要跟这些人搅和  你看他们看你的眼神
Why would you trust these people? and the way they look at you...
他们看我就像圣诞节看见圣诞老人一样
They look at me like it's christmas and I'm santa claus.
我们是他们的救星
They look at us like we're the help.
现在他们得帮我干活了
They work for me now.
我想当我和乔·弗雷泽对垒的时候
I predict that when I meet joe frazier,
会像是一个业余爱好手和真正的职业高手对决
This will be like a good amateur fighting a real professional.
他就象是个参加奥运会的毛头小伙儿
This will be like a kid out of the olympics...
阿里不出三个回合就能把他打倒
Man 1: that's gonna be ali in like three.
和你对阵的不是奥斯卡·伯纳维纳
You're not fighting oscar bonavena,
也不是索尼·里斯顿
You're not fighting sonny liston.
你是在挑战乔·弗雷泽
You're fighting joe frazier.
所有人都知道  那不是重点
Everybody knows that. that's not the point.
他只是说说
He's all talk, man.
好好瞧着阿里怎么蹂躏弗雷泽吧
Look at frazier! ali gonna crush him, baby.
我会打败他的
I'll stop him.
打败我?  就凭你?
Stop me? you?
来吧  我等不急了
How soon? what round?
不要让他逼你出战
Don't let him obligate you. one to 10!
今晚  1971年3月8日  让我们在麦迪逊广场花园
Tonight, march 8, 1971. here we are at madison square garden
一起来见证这场世纪之战吧
For the fight of the century.
无论从任何角度来看  这场比赛都精彩异常
And by anybody's definition, this is a happening.
握手的场面当然会有  美女也会有
There are handshakes and, of course, there are utterly beautiful women.
但在握手和笑容的背后
But behind the smiles and behind the handshakes,
任何人都能感觉到一触即发的紧张气氛
You can feel the atmosphere is so heavy with tension, it's almost unbearable.
今天名角云集
Everybody who is anybody is here.
斯纳特·格齐亚诺  大卫·弗斯特  戴安娜·卡洛尔
Like sinatra. like graziano, david frost and diahann carroll.
伍迪·艾伦和戴安·基顿  绝对的星光灿烂
And woody allen and diane keaton. the celebrities are pouring in.
媒体阵容也相当庞大  生活杂志 时代周刊
The way you all build it up, life magazine cover, time magazine,
每个人都有不同的见解  丹普斯说我会输的
Everybody gives their opinion. dempsey says I'll lose. joe louis...
乔·路易斯也说我会输  正是这样才坚定了我的信心
And when joe louis said I'm gonna lose, that's how I knew I'd won this one.
因为乔·路易斯的预测总是跟结果相反
Joe louis always picks the wrong man!
他的预测永远都跟结果相反
Always picks the wrong man.
乔·路易斯今晚也来了  等着瞧吧
Joe louis is here tonight. watch your ass.
官方公布的乔·弗雷泽的体重是205.5磅
The official weight of joe frazier is 205.5 pounds.
看看他的动作多么迅捷有力
Float like a butterfly, sting like a bee.
你要看比赛吗  鲍勃
You're not watching the fight, bob?
我对拳击不感兴趣
I'm not into boxing.
这可不是拳击
This ain't boxing, kid.
这是政治
It's politics.
我也有些东西给你
I got something for you, too.
是吗
Yeah?
大衣?  给我的吗?
The coat? for me? mmm-hmm.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?
大衣吗?  当然  我很喜欢
The coat? yeah, yeah, it's nice.
你觉得怎样
What do you think? yeah.
-真的吗  -当然
You sure? yeah.
看这儿  珊米
Photographer 1: over here, sammy.
珊米  笑一个
Photographer 2: hey, sammy! give a look.
乔·路易斯  看这儿
Photographer 1: joe louis! over here!
你好吗 弗兰克
How's it going, frank?
你呢  乔
How are you, joe?
女士们  先生们
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
今晚我们众星云集
We have quite a list of introductions.
我们现在介绍今天到场的各界精英大腕儿
We are now going to introduce people from all endeavors of life.
而不只是给个镜头就算了
And not just show people.
因为今晚的明星阵容真是太整齐了
Because everyone is here tonight!
绝对的重头戏
Main event!
第十五轮
Fifteen rounds.
世界重量级拳王争霸赛
For the undisputed heavyweight championship of the world!
阿里  加油
There we go, ali!
来自肯塔基州路易斯韦尔的拳王阿里身着红色披风
From louisville, kentucky, he's wearing red trunks.
阿里  这位是弗兰克·卢卡斯
Champ! this is frank lucas.
阿里的体重是215磅
He weighs 215 pounds.
这就是默罕默德·阿里
Here is muhammad ali!
他的对手来自宾夕法尼亚州费城
His opponent, from philadelphia, pennsylvania,
他身着绿色披风
He's wearing green trunks.
跟卡塔诺打招呼那个人是谁
Who's that laughing with cattano?
他怎么搞到那么靠前的票的
How'd he get so fucking close to the ring?
世界重量级拳王
The heavyweight champion of the world,
乔·弗雷泽!
Joe frazier!
嘿  弗兰克  你要整晚都带着帽子吗
Hey, frank. you gonna keep that hat on all night?
你挡着我了
I'm gonna miss the fight.
谁让你票在我后面呢
You paid for it.
这小虾米顶多是个小供货商  或者皮条客
This guy, he's a supplier at most. or just a pimp.
否则我们肯定有他的案底的
Otherwise we'd know his name.
他的座位比多米尼克·卡塔诺的座位都好  不是吗
His tickets were phenomenal. better seats than dominic cattano. right?
乔·路易斯也跟他握过手
Joe louis shook his hand.
这家伙到底是谁
Who the fuck is this guy?
什么东西
What's this?
是那家伙座的豪华房车的车牌
That's the plate off the limo.
查查是哪家租车公司的
Check with the company who rented it.
看这儿  卢卡斯先生  看这儿
Right there, mr. lucas. right there. good.
我能在这儿拍吗  弗兰克  就在这儿
Photographer 1: can I get a shot here, frank? right here.
蛮帅的  弗兰克
Photographer 2: looking good, frank.
漂亮极了
Beautiful.
好极了
Right on, frank!
祝贺你们
Congratulations!
她是我见过最漂亮的新娘了
She's the most beautiful bride I've ever seen.
威廉姆斯先生  她简直就是我生命的全部
That's my sunshine right there, mr. williams.
我真希望邦比也能见见她
I wish bumpy had met her.
丢给我
Throw it to me!
去拍照
Get a picture.
过来  宝贝儿
Come here, baby.
-怎么了?  -坐好了
What's happening? sit tight.
祝贺你  弗兰克
Congratulations, frank.
警官
Detective.
你确定你这样做道德吗?  我是说她如此的漂亮单纯
So, you sure you done the right thing? I mean, she's beautiful girl and all...
嘿  听着  听着
Hey, hey, listen, listen.
警官先生  在你开口说我和我妻子任何事情以前
Before you say anything about me or about my wife,
请你明白这是我一生中最重要的日子
Understand this is the most important day of my life, detective.
我知道  我当然知道
Oh, I understand. I understand.
你知道吗  一个穿着价值五万美金大衣招摇过市的人
You know, a man who walks around in a $50,000 chinchilla coat
却从来没请我甚至喝过一杯咖啡
And never even bought me a cup of coffee.
弗兰克  这就是你的不对了  你的账单都付了吗
There's something wrong there. pay your bills, frank?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我问你  你的账单都付了吗
Do you pay your bills, I asked you?
如果你没得到你的那份
If you're not getting your share,
也许你该跟你的上司去谈谈
Maybe you need to talk to the chief of police.
我的那份?  你他妈根本都不知道我是谁
what's my share? cause you don't even fucking know me.
也许我是特例
Maybe I'm special.
没错  特例
You are special.
看见这个了吗
You see that right there?
特别调查组
Special investigations unit.
很特别
Special.
明白了吗
Get it?
一万美金  每个月一号
Ten grand. first of each month.
送到这里
Deliver it right here.
-你说完了吗  -恩  说完了
Are you done? oh, yeah, I'm done.
别忘了这个  好好度蜜月
Don't forget your card. have a nice fucking honeymoon.
走
Let's go.
他的名字是弗兰克·卢卡斯
His name is frank lucas.
原籍加州北部的格林斯博罗
Originally from greensboro, north carolina.
因为赌博和非法持枪留下过案底
A couple of arrests years ago. gambling and unlicensed firearm.
他给邦比·约翰逊做了十五年的司机  保镖  打手
For 15 years, he was bumpy johnson's driver, bodyguard and collector.
邦比死的时候就是他送葬的
He was with him when he died.
他有五个兄弟  他是长兄  还有一堆表亲
He's got five brothers. he's the oldest. and a lot of cousins.
他们现在都生活在这里  分散在五个区和新泽西
They all living up here now, spread throughout the five boroughs and jersey.
其中一个兄弟叫德克斯特
The brothers are dexter,
-住在布鲁克林区  是个干洗工  -有什么能帮忙的吗
In brooklyn. he's a dry cleaner. what can I do for you?
取衣服
I'm picking up. yeah.
梅尔文在皇后区开了一家家具店
Melvin in queens has got a custom furniture
同时经营着防火门生意
And fire doors business.
-是这些吗  -没错
That's it right here? right there.
特伦斯在诺瓦克开了家五金店
Terrence in newark, he has a hardware store.
特纳在布朗克斯区开了家轮胎店
Turner in the bronx has got a tire shop.
还有休伊在伯尔根镇有一家修理厂
And huey lucas in bergen county has a body shop.
-你们老板在吗  -就这价了
Is your manager here? that's my price.
少点吧  不然我换地方  怎么样
Oh, man, I'm gonna take it somewhere else, all right?
这些店面都是毒品交易的配送中心
These businesses are the distribution and collection points
同时也都是弗兰克名义上的收入来源
For frank's dope and frank's money.
所有关于弗兰克的资料都让他看起来
Everything about frank's life seems
那么的谦逊  有规矩  守法
Unpretentious, orderly and legitimate.
他每天都早上五点就起床
He starts early, gets up at 5:00 a.m.
几乎每天都自己一个人在哈林区的一家餐馆吃早餐
Has breakfast in a diner in harlem every morning, usually by himself.
然后开始工作  跟他的会计律师见见面之类的
Then he starts work. takes a meeting with the accountant or with his lawyer.
晚上他几乎都待在家里  即使出去
At nights, he usually stays at home. and if he does go out,
也仅和他的妻子或一些球员去固定的几家俱乐部
It's to one of two clubs or a handful of restaurants with his new wife.
那家伙不是他妈的张伯伦吗
Some ball players. that's fucking wilt chamberlain.
朋友都是社会名流  绝不和那些罪犯来往
Friends, musicians. never, never with organized crime guys.
星期日  他会带他母亲去教堂
Sundays, he takes his mother to church.
然后他会去邦比的墓前献花
Then he drives out and he changes
每个周日都是这样  风雨无阻
The flowers on bumpy's grave. every sunday, no matter what.
根本不像一般的毒贩子一样那么招摇
Not the typical day in the life of a dope man, richie.
恩
No.
不过邦比·约翰逊也很低调  尽管他纵横哈林区多年
Bumpy johnson's life wasn't typical either, and he ran harlem for years.
你的意思是说他接了邦比·约翰逊的班
So you're saying that frank lucas replaced bumpy johnson?
-是的  -他的司机
Yeah. his driver?
但是...  但是好像...
But is it? is it? because everything he does...
他在分火鸡
He's handing out turkeys, man.
他的风格跟邦比却不太一样  对吗
He does the same as bumpy would have done, right?
想想谁是邦比最亲近的人呢
And who was bumpy most likely to teach?
邦比每天都要见到他
The guy he sees every day.
就像意大利的家族黑帮一样
It's like a sicilian family.
他也用同样的组织结构来保护自己
He's structured his organization to protect him in the same way.
如果他跟了邦比很长时间
And if he was with bumpy for so long,
那就说明他和那些意大利人的来往肯定很密切
That means he would have spent a lot of time with italians.
密切到对他们的做法了如指掌
Definitely long enough to learn that much.
但是我觉得弗兰克后面
But here's the thing. I don't think it's frank lucas that we're after.
还有更大的鱼
Who we want is whoever frank lucas is working for.
就是那个帮他毒品运进美国的家伙
It's whoever's actually bringing the heroin in.
好吧  你现在对他掌握多少了
Okay. so what do you have on him
有什么证据能扳倒他吗
That will stick in court? because this isn't it.
没有毒品  没有证人  就没人会被送进监狱的
Without powder, without informants, no one's going to jail.
我知道
That's understood, sir.
除非我们非常非常幸运
And I don't think we're gonna get informants, not from inside the family,
否则我们不可能从他们家族内部突破
You know, unless we get very, very lucky.
实验室分析表明
Straight up lab tests suggesting
蓝色魔法的纯度和亚洲货一致
Purity's consistent with asian dope.
我们都知道  意大利人通常和欧洲人
The italians, we know, usually work with other europeans
或者土耳其人交易
Or with the turks.
小包装蓝色魔法的踪迹遍及
We got small blue packets turning up
整个三州交界区域的所有街区
In neighborhoods all over the tri-state area.
从唐人街到黑人区  再到华盛顿高地
From chinatown, to harlem, washington heights,
甚至里奇蒙德大街或者到斯代顿岛
Richmond avenue and staten island.
他们覆盖了北橘子郡  普林斯顿  贝永  诺瓦克
They got north orange, princeton, bayonne, newark,
斯拉克斯  罗切斯特  水牛城这些地方
Syracuse, rochester, buffalo, and all the way through connecticut.
都是一样的毒品
The same dope.
火鸡来了
All right.
放那儿吧
That's it, down there.
来  手拉手祷告吧
Okay, let's all join hands.
主啊  感谢你赐予我们这些食物
Lord, we thank you for this food we're about to receive,
使我们不至于饥饿
The nourishments of our bodies.
纯洁我们的灵魂  以耶稣的名义
Feed our souls with heavenly grace, in jesus' name and for his sake.
-阿门  -阿门
Amen. amen.
别怕  别怕  没事的
Hey, it's okay. it's okay. come on, now.
没事的
It's okay. shh.
你准备好了吗  老家伙
You better get yourself ready, old man.
尽管放马过来吧
Come on, big man. throw the ball.
准备好了  我要投了
Get yourself ready, old man. all right!
你老爸说你有一只手很厉害
Come on, now. your pop said you had an arm on you. come on!
梅尔文叔叔  我要打的你满地找牙
I'm gonna set your ass in the grass, uncle melvin.
你省口气吧  尽管放马过来
Hey! watch your mouth, boy. throw the ball!
梅尔文叔叔  我是个投手  不是外场手
Damn, uncle melvin, I'm a pitcher, not an outfielder!
史蒂夫 过来
Steve. steve, come here.
过来  坐
Come, sit down.
有事吗  弗兰克叔叔
Uncle frank. what's happening?
你最近好吗
How you doing?
不错啊
Cool.
想喝点什么吗
You want a drink?
你最知道我不喝酒
You know better than that.
试试你
Just checking.
上次见面你去那儿了
Why didn't you show up for that meeting, steve?
我和那些扬基俱乐部的人还有比利·马丁都说好了
I set it up with the yankees and billy martin.
你为什么没来
Why didn't you show up?
别骗我
Don't lie to me.
我不想再打球了
I don't want to play ball no more.
-我想好了  -你说什么
I decided. what you talking about?
你想好了?  想好什么了
You decided? decided what?
这不是我想要的
That ain't what I want.
你胡说些什么?  你从小屁孩就开始打球
What you talking about? you've been playing since you was a little boy.
都可以进入职业队了  你怎么...
You were ready to go into the pros. what you...
弗兰克!  有点麻烦
Frank! we got a problem, man.
你到底想怎么样
What do you want?
我想像你一样
I want what you got, uncle frank.
I want to be you.
稀释的太厉害了
He's been diluting it so much.
比以往纯度少了两三个百分点
We're down 2%%, 3%% pure.
你亲自试过了?
And you tested it? you're sure?
是的
Yeah.
你看什么看
Fuck you looking at?
伙计
My man.
欢迎啊  弗兰克
Welcome, frank. how you doing, nick?
-你好吗  尼克  -事事顺心  欢迎啊
How you doing, nick? it's all great. welcome.
-我想跟你谈谈  -好啊  来吧
I need to talk to you. great. come on.
嘿  你们都给我出去
Hey, you all, everybody get out! let's go.
快点  快点
Come on! hurry up!
坐  兄弟
Sit, my brother.
我听说你跟查理聊过了
I take it you talked to charlie.
我想你肯定想多知道点我的新玩法
Guess you wanna hear more about my black coalition.
-我演示给你看  -不  不  不
Let me explain to you... no, no, no.
行了  行了
I'm all right.
尼克  我可不是为那个来找你的
That's not what I came here for, nick.
大家都很满意
Yeah, everybody's good, nick.
我知道大家都很满意  查理  巴兹  还有意大利人
You know, everybody's happy. charlie, baz, the italians,
除了你之外大家都很满意
You know, johnny law. everybody's happy except you.
我很满意啊  弗兰克
I'm happy, frank.
你满意吗?  真的吗？
You happy? really?
也许我会让你不满意的
Well, maybe I'm the one with the problem.
继续  继续
Yeah, go on. get one.
好吧
All right.
我只是不明白
I gotta problem 'cause
为什么你非得要
I don't understand why you gotta take
把我的好货搞成那样
Something that's perfectly good
砸我的招牌
And mess it up.
看见了吗  这可是个品牌
See, brand names.
品牌很重要  知道吗
Brand names mean something. understand?
别他妈吵了
Shut the fuck up!
继续  弗兰克
Go ahead, frank.
太吵了  不好意思
I'm sorry about that bullshit.
蓝色魔法
Blue magic.
那就是品牌
That's a brand name.
就像是百事可乐一样  那是个品牌
Like pepsi, that's a brand name.
我让他保质  并且保量
I stand behind it. I guarantee it.
即使他们根本都不认识我
They know that, even if they don't know me any more than
他们也会认这个牌子
They know the chairman of general mills.
你都说些什么啊  弗兰克
What the fuck are you talking about, frank?
我在说你把我的蓝色魔法
What I'm talking about is when you chop my dope down
一分为二 为三  为四
To one, two, three, four, five percent
然后你还继续叫他蓝色魔法
And then you call it blue magic,
那你就是在砸我的招牌  是侵权
That is trademark infringement.
你明白我说什么吗
You understand what I'm saying?
弗兰克  我买了货  我有权利决定怎么卖它
With all due respect, frank, if I buy something, I own it.
不是这么回事
No, that ain't true. that ain't true.
我买辆车  我想怎么弄就能怎么弄  那是我的自由
If I buy a car, and I wanna paint it, I can paint the motherfucker.
我知道  但是你没必要这么做了
Yeah, but you don't have to.
这就是我说的  你没必要这么做
This is what I'm saying to you, nick, you don't have to.
利润已经够高了
Good enough the way it is.
只要保证蓝色魔法的招牌
You can make enough money off it
就能让你财源不断
The way it is, just by calling it blue magic.
要是你还想要更多  就有点过了
Anything more than that is greed, son.
那你想让我怎么办  弗兰克  改品牌吗
What you want, frank? you want me to change the name on it?
我坚持你最好改个名字
I would have to insist that you change the name.
那好吧  那我就叫他红色魔法好了
Fine by me, frank. I'll call it red magic,
尽管听起来不那么顺口
Even though that don't sound as good.
我不管你叫什么
I don't give a fuck what you call it.
只要不砸了我招牌
Put a chokehold on the motherfucker
你叫他蓝色狗屎我都不管  你明白我的意思吗
And call it blue dog shit, you know what I mean?
你要再让我抓住那么做
I don't care, just don't let me catch you doing this again.
抓住我?  侵权?  坚持?
Catch me? infringement? insist?
我可不喜欢那些文绉绉的词
I don't like these words as much as,
不好意思打扰你了  尼克
"please, thank you, I'm sorry to bother you, nicky."
你不请自来  在我的地盘应该恭敬一点才对
These are better words you use to come to my motherfucking club
你明白吗
Without an invitation! you hear me?
伙计
My man.
妈的  后面是警察吗
Oh, shit. fuck, is that the cops there, man?
没事
It's all right.
他们想干嘛  给我们开罚单吗
The hell they're gonna do, give us a ticket?
弗兰克  车里有货啊
Stuff's in the car, frank.
什么?
What?
车里有些货
Some of it's in the trunk.
-你过得好吗  弗兰克?  -我很好  你怎么样  侦探?
How you doing, frank? I'm good. how you doing, detective?
感恩节过得如何?
How was your thanksgiving?
不好  你怎么不下车?
Not so good, as a matter of fact. why don't you get out of the car?
爽快点  他妈的把钥匙给我
Come on, give me the fucking keys.
谢尔比哪去了?  离职啦?
Where's the shelby at? the shelby's gone?
谢尔比不在啦  弗兰克  站那儿别动
The shelby's gone, frank. stay right there.
没问题
Yes, sir. right here.
看看你有什么好东西?
You got anything worth looking at in here?
那家伙是特鲁普
Hey, that's that trupo guy.
-真的?  -对
Is that him? yeah.
败类!
Fucking prick.
-弗兰克  过来一下  -好
Come over here a minute, frank. yeah.
我们应该怎么办?
What are we gonna do about this?
什么也不要做  把它塞进车里  关上后备箱
We don't do shit about it. we close it up, throw it back in the trunk,
大家都回家去吃点南瓜饼  喝点苹果酒
Everybody go home, have some pumpkin pie, warm apple cider.
我有一个更好的主意
I got a better idea.
不如我把你们俩扔进河里?
Or would you rather me throw you and your brother in the fucking river?
或者下次我们炸了你的家!
Would you rather your house blows up next time?
-我很喜欢那辆车  -了解
I loved that car. I know.
他在干什么? 摇下车窗!
What's he doing? shakedown!
看来有人要顺手牵羊了
Somebody's getting some money for the benevolent fund.
真是人渣
Look at that shit.
对不起 弗兰克
Sorry, frank.
没关系  先上车
It's all right. go and get in the car.
好的  给我回电话
All right, you call me back.
国安局  税局  联邦调查局
Ins, irs, FBI.
我从他们那里得不到任何有用的资料
I can't get a damn thing out of any of them.
因为他们认为你和黑帮是一伙儿的
Because they all think you're on the take.
而你却认为他们才是蛇鼠一窝
And you think they are.
你知道  我觉得他们并不想完全禁绝贩毒
You know, I don't think they want this to stop.
有太多的人从中受益
I think it employs too many people.
法官  律师  警察  政治家
Judges, lawyers, cops, politicians,
狱警  假释官
Prison guards, probation officers.
如果他们停止贩毒
They stop bringing dope into this country,
会有十万人没了饭碗
About 100,000 people are going to be out of a job.
找头儿的
Spearman.
我们是联邦调查局的  来找罗伯特警官
FBI. here to see detective roberts.
谁泄漏出来的?  我认识的人吗?  我妻子?
So who took it out? somebody I know? my wife?
如果有人悬赏要我的命
Come on, if somebody's taking a contract
我应该知道的
Out on my life, I'd like to know.
我不能泄露  你能理解吗?
I can't say without compromising our source. you understand?
不  这和和我的生命有关
No. not when it's my life, I don't understand.
如果你想要  我们可以派人来保护你
If you want we can assign someone to you.
联邦调查局的保护
FBI protection.
你知道吗? 我的生命本来就已经够危险了
You know what? my life is dangerous enough as it is.
那我们就不再浪费你们的时间了  继续你的工作吧
Well, we'll let you get back to your business.
好吧  拉里  鲍勃
Okay. larry, bob.
欢迎来到"花园之州"
Thanks for visiting the garden state.
小心点
Take care.
喂  你知道弗兰克·卢卡斯吗?
Hey, what do you know about frank lucas?
我们知道你总在打听他
We know that you keep calling about him.
我们相信和平就要到来
We believe that peace is at hand.
很快就可以达成协议了
We believe that an agreement is within sight.
像我以前说过的...
As I said earlier...
对
Yeah.
喂  乔伊
Hey, joey. hi.
好的  明天  为什么?
All right. yeah, tomorrow. why?
微波是他妈的啥玩意儿?
What the fuck is a microwave?
是科技的力量  就像原子弹一样
It's a scientific force, like atomic energy.
真的?
Yeah? yeah.
它可以重新排列分子  产生巨大的能量
It rearranges the molecules.
重新排列什么?  爆米花?
Of what? of what? of popcorn.
排列你的榆木脑袋  尝尝吧
Of your head. stick it in. go on.
我可以给你搞一个
I can get you one of those.
全新的  和这个一样  我叫人发货给你
Brand new, just like this. I'll have it delivered.
不用  谢谢
No, thank you.
这是哪?
Hey. where is that?
阿斯本  我们刚回去过
Aspen. we just got back.
玩得不错  你猜我们碰到谁了?
Had a great time. you know who we met?
谁?
Who?
伯特·雷诺兹
Burt reynolds.
-真的吗?  -真的  不骗你
Yeah? yeah? yeah. I'm not kidding.
好莱圬好多明星都去那里疯狂购物
A lot people from hollywood go up there now. they're buying up everything.
-这是你家?  -不是
This is your place? mmm.
你知道这值多少钱?  可以滑雪进去和出来  有五间卧室
You know what that's worth? ski in, ski out. five bedrooms.
桑拿  什么都有  我们只是客人
Sauna. everything. we were guests.
那是你的地方
It's your place.
我们可不可以想点办法
Isn't there something we can do,
不要去骚扰那个大人物?
About leaving the big guy alone?
你知道我在说谁
You know who I mean.
如果我不向上级报告你刚才所说的  我会有麻烦的
I don't report what you just said, I can get in a lot of trouble.
如果我报告了  你就会有麻烦
I do report it, then the trouble is yours.
我希望你不会那样做
I'm hoping you won't do that.
瑞奇  别闹了  我没有录音
Richie, come on. I'm not taping it.
你怎么知道?  因为我们是朋友
How do you know? because we're friends.
我告诉你  这个礼物是真的
And I'm telling you, this is a real offer.
谁给的? 你叔叔?
From who? your uncle?
你为什么要这么做?  我们会连朋友都没得做
Why would you do this? why would you risk our friendship?
因为
Because
我很担心你
I care what happens to you.
你不应该那么做的
You shouldn't have done this.
我没有别的选择  你也一样  瑞奇!
I had to, I had no choice. neither do you. richie!
你别无选择  不要碰弗兰克·卢卡斯
You don't have a choice. just leave frank lucas alone.
弗兰克·卢卡斯?
Frank lucas?
嗯
Yeah.
你告诉玛丽我得走了  抱歉
You tell marie I had to leave. I'm sorry.
告诉她原因
Tell her why.
-别开枪!  -快说!
Don't shoot! don't shoot! talk! talk! don't shoot!
-你是瑞奇·罗伯特?  -是的  那又怎么样?
Are you richie roberts? yes, so what?
你的传票  对不起
You've been served. I'm sorry.
好吧
All right.
罗莉
Laurie.
对不起  我没有给你想要的那种生活
Look, I'm sorry I never gave you the kind of life you wanted, all right.
很抱歉以前做的不够
I'm sorry it was never enough.
但是不要因为我诚实而惩罚我
Don't punish me for being honest.
不要夺走我的孩子
Don't take my boy away.
你说什么?  你觉得我是因为你诚实?
What are you saying? that because you were honest
你不像其他警察那样捞黑钱我才离开你?
And you didn't take money like every other cop, I left you?
你不捞黑钱只有一个原因
No, you don't take money for one reason.
只是为了博取诚实的名声来掩盖别的东西
To buy being dishonest about everything else.
那比捞黑钱更让人恶心
And that's worse than taking money nobody gives a shit about.
卖毒品的钱和赌博的钱  谁不想要?
Drug money, gambling money nobody's gonna miss.
我宁可你拿那些钱  也要你对我诚实
You know, I'd rather you took it and been honest with me.
或者不拿  我也不在乎  但是不要欺骗我
Or don't take it. I don't care. but then don't go cheat on me.
不要欺骗孩子  不要总在外面鬼混而没时间陪他
Don't cheat on your kid by never being around. don't go out and get laid
不要和你的那些红颜知己婊子们睡觉
By your snitches and your secretaries and strippers!
我一眼就能看出来  她就是其中一个
I can tell by just looking, she's one of them.
你...
You...
你以为你诚实就可以上天堂  你绝对上不了天堂
You think you're going to heaven because you're honest, but you're not.
你将和你所不屑的那些警察们一起去地狱
You're going to the same hell as the crooked cops you can't stand.
起立
All rise.
请坐
Please be seated.
迪肯森小姐
Miss dickerson,
在法庭宣判前
Before the court renders its opinion,
你还有什么要说的?
Is there anything else you'd like to be heard on?
是的  法官
Yes, your honor.
今天讲了很多有关
Your honor, a lot has been said here today about how unsavory
罗伯特先生的生活环境如何危险以及对小孩不好的话
Mr. roberts' environment is for a child. how dangerous it is.
但是他是负责来保护我们的  我们给了他这样的责任
We tell him to protect us. we give him that responsibility,
然后我们却说  我们不相信他可以养好小孩
But then say, "oh, we don't trust you to raise a child.
我们认为你并不适合
"we don't think you're fit for that."
我是不适合
I'm not.
你说的对
You're right.
我没有足够的条件养育孩子
Being around me is no place for a kid.
你把他带到维加斯去吧  我有空就去看他
You take him to vegas. I'll come see him when I can.
法官  很抱歉浪费了法庭的时间
Your honor, I want to apologize for wasting the court's time.
德克
Doc.
我看见他们了
I see them.
他来了
There he is.
他在做什么?
The fuck is this guy doing?
喂  香槟
Hey! champagne.
-圣诞快乐  -给我们的?
Merry christmas, detectives. for us?
对  好好享受吧
Yeah. enjoy that.
玩得开心点
You fellas have a good time. mmm-hmm.
这是克里斯托在作现场报道
It's cristal.
南越部队召来飞机进行轰炸
South vietnamese troops called in air strikes
攻击市内的共产党的据点
On communist positions inside the city.
按潜规则办事  这是一回事
Paying off johnny law, that's one thing.
这本来不是什么问题
There ain't no problem with that.
我十岁起就一直在给警察钱
I've been paying off the police since I was 10 years old.
把他们的孩子送到大学  获得国家荣誉奖章
Put more of their kids through college than the national merit award.
一个又一个...
Give me one of them round one... yeah.
这次有点不同...
This is different, though. these...
他们是专门调查组的  这完全是他们自己的问题
Special investigative unit. that's their problem. they think they're special.
杂种  一点职业道德都没有
Fucking crooks. no code of ethics.
你看怎么样?
What do you think?
太漂亮了
Looks great. it's beautiful.
好
Good.
我担心的并不只有警察
The police, that ain't the only somebody I'm worried about.
我看到不认识的人和车
I seeing cars where I ain't never seen them before, people I don't know.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
圣诞快乐  查理
Merry christmas, charlie.
谢谢
Thank you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
拿下这个
Here, take this.
我吃一片面包  马上就走
A quick toast, and then I'll be off.
这里发生的事情是一场战争意外
What happened here was an accident of war.
有人犯了错误
Somebody made a mistake.
邦比很久没有出来过了
Bumpy ain't hardly ever go out no more.
从某个时候开始  他就待在家里
After a certain point he stayed in the house.
看电视
Watch tv.
下棋  看报纸
Play chess. read the newspaper.
我想他只是想过点安静的生活
I thought he was just trying to lead the quiet life,
但实际上  他哪也不能去
But no, he couldn't go nowhere.
哪都不安全
Not without something happening.
弗兰克...
Frankie...
我们仍然可以出去
We can still go out.
和谁? 到哪里?
With who? where?
和...
Well, with...
但有人在监视他
But I know he's under surveillance.
也许再也不能和我家人
Ain't gonna be no christmas time
这里一起过圣诞了
With my family being here no more.
你给他们钱不就完了吗?
Why don't you just pay who you have to pay?
给了  上百上千万的钱
I do pay them. I pay thousands and millions
给小毒贩  警察
To dope dealers, crooks, cops.
每个人我都给
I pay everybody.
我付的比他们应得的多
I pay more than they should get.
但他们从来不知足!
I can't satisfy nobody!
就像吸毒一样! 每个人都很歇斯底里!
It's like dope! everybody's strung out!
你给的越多  他们就要的越多
The more you give 'em, the more they want.
他们总是想多要点
They expect more.
弄成恶性循环了
Give more and they want more.
你想出去吗?
Do you want to go out?
好的  穿上衣服
All right, baby. put something of what you got.
-我? -对
Should i? yeah.
这是圣诞精神
That's christmas spirit.
这就对了嘛
That's what I'm talking about. feliz navidad.
穿漂亮点儿
Something nice? mmm-hmm.
我们将会过得很愉快
We're going to have a great time.
对  淇塔
That's right, chica.
卢卡斯  祝您愉快
Mr. lucas. enjoy your evening.
现在没什么状况了
It's all clear.
尼克
Nicky!
那是谁? 是你的人尼克  看见了吗?
Who is that? there's your boy, nicky. see him?
看见了吗?
Know what I'm saying?
我看见了  继续开
Yeah, I see him. let's keep going.
要转回来吗?
Around back?
不要  我不会偷偷溜进我自己的俱乐部
Hell, no. I ain't sneaking into my own club.
难以置信
Incredible. huh?
来吧
Come on.
等等
Hold on. hold on.
怎么啦?
What?
我想在车里等
I want to wait in the car.
弗兰克  让我去弄就行了
Frank, I got it. I got it. I'll wait for it. I got it.
要那种黄色的酱  黄色的
Get that yellow sauce. yellow sauce.
还有鸡  宫爆鸡丁
And the chicken. the kung pao chicken.
把暖气打开好吗?
Can you turn the heater on?
该死  我去拿钥匙
Shit. I'm gonna go get the keys.
-德克  把钥匙给我  -给你
Doc, give me the keys. here you go.
德克!
Doc!
快下车
Get out of the car.
-你还好吗? -没事
You okay? yeah.
该死的
Shit.
你怎么样?
Come on, baby. you all right?
我们走
Let's go.
是尼克干的?
Was it nicky?
不管是不是他干的  我们马上去杀了他
We'll go right now and fucking kill him whether it was him or not,
只要你下一个命令  弗兰克
You say the word, frankie.
我们得有所行动
We got to do something, frank.
不能光坐在这里
We can't just sit here.
我们要走了
We're leaving.
大家都回去吧
All right, everybody get out. you all right, man?
今天是圣诞节  去和家人待在一块
Go on home. it's christmas time. go and be with your families.
我很好
I'm all right.
走呀  去陪你们的孩子
Go on. go ahead. be with your kids.
走吧
Go ahead.
你要去哪里?
Where are we gonna go, huh?
我们去西班牙  或者  中国?
We're gonna go to spain, somewhere? china?
别闹了  坐下  说说你想去哪
Huh? come on, sit down. tell me where you want to go.
弗兰克  我们哪都可以去
Frank, we can go anywhere we want.
-不行  -我们在哪生活都行  弗兰克
No, we can't. we can live anywhere, frank.
去哪里? 然后呢? 逃跑? 躲藏?
Where? and do what? run? hide?
弗兰克·卢卡斯不会怕任何人
Frank lucas don't run from nobody, baby.
我们哪里也不去  就在这里待着
We ain't going nowhere. we're gonna stay right here.
这是我的家
We're gonna stay right here. this is my home.
我的生意  我的妻子  母亲和家庭都在这里
This is where my business is, my wife, my mother, my family.
这是我的国家  我哪也不去
My country. I ain't going nowhere.
我不会因为怕任何人而逃离
I ain't running from nobody!
这是美国
This is America.
你也得留在这里!
And you ain't going nowhere, either!
啊?
Huh?
华盛顿时间27日7点
A ceasefire, internationally supervised, will begin
停火协议将会生效
At 7:00 p.m. this saturday, january 27th, washington time.
我一会给你打电话
I'll call you back.
喂! 你在做什么?
Hey! what are you doing?
瑞奇
Richie.
我听说科西嘉黑帮朝弗兰克开了一枪
So, what I hear it was the corsican mob took a shot at frank.
是法国贩毒集团在美国的人干的 菲尔南多·雷
You know, french connection, fernando rey,
一个被弗兰克挤出了市场的毒贩
The exporters that frank has put out of business.
在纽约我可以搞定
Look, I can take care of him in new york.
但是我不想总是担心
I just don't want to have to worry that every time
每次他开车过桥去泽西的时候
He drives across the bridge to jersey,
可能会被人暗杀
Someone's gonna take another shot at him.
瑞奇  我们得一起合作
Richie, you and I gotta start working together.
我们需要更加努力
We need to step up our efforts.
下次他们的枪法会更准
Next time, their aim could be better.
我们得让这头肥牛活着
We need to keep this cash cow alive.
看看你在做什么?
What the fuck are you doing here?
你要捉弗兰克·卢卡斯?  你哪儿出毛病啦?
Were you actually gonna arrest frank lucas? what's the matter with you?
-你不知道吗?  -不知道
What, you don't know? no.
新泽西的每个人都是疯子
Everybody in new jersey's crazy. oh.
你知道我们是干什么的  警察就是抓坏人的
You know what we do here? cops arrest bad guys.
在你上桥之前
Before you get on that bridge again,
先给我打电话  确保那里是安全的
You should call me first, just make sure it's safe.
我比我的朋友们更聪明  我可以保证你的安全
"i'm more enlightened than some of my friends. I can guarantee you peace of mind."
这是你讲过的  多米尼克
That's what you told me, dominic.
我可以保证你的安全
"i can guarantee you peace of mind!"
我现在一点也不安全
I don't feel so peaceful!
我妻子差点被杀了!
They tried to kill my wife!
他们是谁?
Who was that? huh?
也许是你们的人
Maybe it was one of your peoples.
-我不知道  -你不知道?  -不知道
I don't know yet. no. you don't know?
你不知道
You don't know.
我知道的我会告诉你  我也许应该
I'll tell you what I know. maybe I should just put 500 guns
在街上放500个枪手开始杀些人
Out there on the street and just start shooting up some people,
这样才能有点作用
Just to make a point.
弗兰克  刺杀你的可能是瘾君子  可能是竞争对手
Frank, it was a junkie. it was a rival. some dumb-ass kid
也可能是个想出名的小子 或是某个你忘了打点的人
Trying to make a name for himself. somebody you forgot to pay off.
也许你得罪了某人但你不知道
Someone you slighted without even realizing it.
也许是你被排挤得没了活路的的竞争对手
Could be someone you put out of business from being so successful. look at you.
你的成功给你招来了不少敌人
Success, it's got enemies, frank. lots of enemies.
是成功害了你  你能怎么做?
So your success took a shot at you. what are you gonna do now?
你能怎么办?  退出江湖?
How you gonna kill it? you're gonna become unsuccessful?
弗兰克  如果我们想成功  就一定会树敌的
Frank, we can be successful and have enemies, right?
除非我们不想成功  你知道  我们也结交了一些朋友
Or we can be unsuccessful, too, you know, we can have friends.
我们只能这样做
That's the choice we make.
北越的军队已经打到了西贡
The final evacuation of military and diplomatic personnel
我们正在彻夜疏散军事和外交人员
Continued throughout the night, as north vietnamese troops marched on saigon.
西贡的陷落迫在眉睫
The imminent fall of the city has brought
人们日渐绝望
chaos and a growing sense of desperation.
国际长途
International.
请稍等
One moment, please.
喂  内特
Yeah, nate.
喂  弗兰克  怎么啦?
Hey, frank. what's up, baby?
你那里怎么样?
What's going on over there?
全完了
It's all over.
我看到新闻了  那边到底怎么样了?
Yeah, I'm watching the news. what the hell's going on?
结束了  弗兰克
The game's over, frank.
唔  结束了
Huh? it's done.
大家都要回家了  和平要到来了
Everybody going home, baby. give peace a chance.
听我说 这事没完...
Well, look, I'm not... listen to me.
我要两
I want two...
我要你空运两千公斤货过来
I want 2,000 keys in the air.
不可能  我们的资源都撤走了  没法再做了
It's impossible, frank. all our resources are going home. it's over.
我要过去  我来教你做
I'll tell you what. I'm on my way over there.
-现在? 别开玩笑了  -没错
Right now? oh, come... yeah.
你敢偷我东西?
You stole my shit?
-斯比尔曼  快醒醒  -怎么啦?
Spearman, wake the fuck up, man. what?
我的货哪去了  亲爱的?
Where's my shit, darlynn?
不要伤害我  吉米
Don't hurt me, jimmy!
天啊! ...警察! 警察!
Jesus! what the... police! police!
把枪放下  吉米! 把枪放下!
Drop the gun, jimmy! drop the gun!
举起手来! 吉米 把枪放下!
Let me see your hands! jimmy, drop the fucking gun!
我不是开玩笑的  吉米! 小心我打爆你的头!
I'm not playing with you, jimmy! I'll blast your fucking head off!
别开枪! 别开枪!
Don't shoot! don't shoot!
这是你的枪  还有你的指纹
I got your gun and I got your prints.
你知道这是什么? 谋杀未遂
You know what you got? you got attempted murder.
要坐十五年牢!
Fifteen fucking years!
谋杀未遂和谋杀的判罚是一样的
Attempted murder is the same as murder one, that's a grand jury.
但是只要你肯跟我们合作
Now, a grand jury could come back favorably.
我们会让法官站在你这边
It could be reduced to manslaughter.
也许这只是一般案件
All right? maybe even self-defense.
甚至是正当防卫
It all just depends on how we wanna deal with you.
让我们来看看接下来会怎么样  吉米?
See where this is fucking going, jimmy?
我们说你躲过这次  你想想你表哥弗兰克会怎么想?
Let's say you beat it. what you think your cousin frank is gonna think?
他有一天会知道
Right, he is gonna know, at some point in time,
我们曾经坐在一起像这样谈话
We sat you down, and we talked to you like this.
然后在法庭上判你无罪
And then you go to court and you beat attempted murder?
弗兰克会怎么看?  他可一点也不笨!
What's he gonna think? is he stupid? is your cousin frank stupid?
回答问题!
Answer him!
他会认为你已经招供了.
No. he's going to assume that you talked.
但是现在  弗兰克还不知道你的事
But right now, frank doesn't know.
你是想让弗兰克在报纸上看到这些呢?
You want frank to read about this in the papers?
还是想平安地从这里走出去?
Or do you just want to walk out of here?
没有保释  不会有审判  不会坐牢  你今天就可以回家
No bail, no trial, no jail, just walk out of here today.
你看着办吧
Your choice.
罂粟不会因为战争而消失
Opium plants are hard enough to outlive any war.
美军撤走以后罂粟还会继续开花结果
They'll still be here long after the troops have gone.
但没有了美国飞机你怎么能运输它们呢?
What are you going to do for transportation when the last us plane goes home?
我会想办法的
I'll figure something out.
我会再来找你的  一定
You will see me again, that's for sure.
我知道这样说不符合我的最佳利益  弗兰克
It is not in my best interest to say this, frank,
不过激流勇退
But quitting while you're ahead
和放弃是不一样的
Is not the same as quitting.
喂
Yeah. hey.
叫他过来
Go get him.
-你要去哪里  -马上我就回来
What are you want to do, baby. one second.
是我  弗兰克
It's frank. yeah.
喂
Yeah.
诺瓦克
Newark.
临时
Short term,
3号停车场
Parking lot three.
临时3号停车场
Short term, lot three.
就是以前说过的那辆"野马"?
That's the mustang we talking about, right?
车牌号是多少?
okay, right. what's the plate number?
K-a... k-a...
760  76
760. 76.
-0  -好
Zero. all right.
诺瓦克没有临时3号停车场这个地方
There's no short term lot three at newark.
这是个字谜
They got letters. a-b-c-d. I know.
也许是指时间  3:00?
Maybe he means a time. 3:00?
这个车牌既不是新泽西的也不是纽约的
This isn't no jersey license plate, nor new york, for that matter.
-K-a-7-6-0?  -对
K-a-7-6-0? yup.
基罗  阿尔法?
Kilo alpha?
是飞机的牌号?
A plane tail number?
基罗  阿尔法 760
Kilo alpha 760.
你查一下商业飞机  你们查私人飞机
You check commercial planes. you guys check private planes.
从最小的飞机到最大的飞机一个也不要遗漏
Everything, from a little fucking cessna to the biggest fucking whatever jet.
好吗?
All right?
我来查军队的飞机  你要去哪里  吉米?
I'll check military planes. where you going, jimmy?
你哪也不能去...坐下
You're not going anywhere. sit... sit down.
-机长先生?  -我就是
Captain? yeah?
瑞奇·罗伯特  伊塞克斯县警察  我知道你在等我们
Richie roberts. essex county. I know you're expecting us.
这是搜查令  我们要查一下这飞机
Here's our warrant. we're looking on the plane.
等等! 等等!
Wait! wait!
斯哥特  拦住这些士兵  检查一下他们的行李
Scotty, stop all these soldiers! check their bags. every one of them.
破门搜查令
No-knock warrant.
-先查楼上  -他们要去哪?
All right. start upstairs. where are they going?
亲爱的  进来
Step in, sweetie.
夫人  请坐
Ma'am, please sit down.
这是在干什么?
What is this?
喂  喂  喂! 停下
Whoa, whoa, whoa! all this stops! hey. hey. hey.
所有人和物品都不能离开!  减速!
Nothing leaves this area, all right? just slow down with this.
好吧  把那些卡车拦截下来  别走
All right. stop these trucks. hold on, hold on.
把机舱璧上的东西都扯下来
Everything off the walls! just pull it all down.
这可是个庞然大物  瑞奇
Damn thing's a monster, rich.
这是做什么?
What is this?
我们要检查这里的每一个人每一件行李
Nothing leaves this area till we've checked it.
所有东西只有在检查过后才能放行
All right, captain. nothing.
我们要检查整个飞机  也要查那些卡车
We got to take the plane down, we got to look in the trucks.
每个人都要检查
Every man here gets searched.
你看看搜查令就明白了
Read the warrant, sir.
你丈夫光彩的事业就要结束了
Your husband's illustrious career is over.
联邦政府会马上过来  带走所有的东西
The feds are gonna come in, gonna take everything.
在那之前  我得捞点东西
And then they're gonna take it all. but not before I get my gratuity.
钱放在哪里?
So where's the money?
你在说什么? 什么钱?
What are you talking about? what money?
什么钱?
What am I talking about? what money?
弗兰克存的给所有人的逃命钱
The getaway money that frank and every other gangster keeps in his house.
如果你现在就走 也许弗兰克不会杀你
If you leave now, there's a chance frank might not kill you.
闭嘴  坐下
Shut up! sit down!
坐下
Sit down!
国防部今天宣布撤退计划
Defense today announced the planned evacuation
所有余下的美军武装从越南撤离
Of all remaining us combat forces from vietnam,
对某些人来说消息来的太迟了
News that comes too late for some,
在这  多佛空军基地庄严的停机坪上
As here, on a solemn tarmac at dover air force base.
这架c-130运输机装载着令人悲伤的货物
This c-130, loaded down with its sorrowful cargo,
承载着最英勇的美国士兵  运送他们到最后的安息地
A cargo of America's bravest and best, en route to their final resting places.
伙计们  把棺材抬下去
You guys. take this coffin down.
-打开  -我不打
Open it. I'm not doing that.
狗够凶的啊?
Great fucking dog, huh?
你马上停下
You stop this, right now.
我的搜查令有权检查这架飞机
My warrant gives me permission to examine this plane,
这架飞机和装的货
The plane and its cargo.
好  可是你没得到我的允许
Well, you don't have my permission.
我不需要你的允许  机长
I don't need it, captain.
别急  别叫  孩子  嘿  过来
Easy! easy, boy. come on. hey!
弗兰  让开
Frank, move out of the way.
该死的
Damn.
够了
That's enough!
盯着棺材  别让它们离开你的视线
Stay with these coffins. do not let them out of your sight.
明白了
Got it. okay.
嘿  帮我把这个搬开
Hey. help me out with this.
那是架军用运输机
That was a military transport plane.
如果上面有海洛因的话
If there was heroin was onboard,
那一定有军方的人卷入了
Then someone in the military would have to be involved.
意味着打一场牺牲了5万名士兵的战争的同时
Which means that even as it fights a war that's claimed
军方正在走私毒品
50,000 American lives, the military is smuggling narcotics.
那就是对今天这事作出的解释
That is how this event today will be interpreted.
就因为我们这个机构的某些员工相信
That someone employed by this office
美国军方参与了毒品走私
Believes that the united states army is in the drug trafficking business
正在寻找证据  所以不惜这些年轻烈士的遗体被亵渎
And is trying to prove it by desecrating the remains of young men
他们已经为保家卫国而献身
Who have given their lives in the defense of democracy!
-这架飞机上有毒品  -闭上你的臭嘴!
There is dope on that plane. shut the fuck up!
你有没有想过你的行为
Is it any wonder, then, because of your actions,
已经让整个联邦禁毒体系岌岌可危
The entire federal narcotics program is now in jeopardy
这个体系正在被彻底而疯狂的摧毁
Of being dismantled as completely and enthusiastically
就像这他妈的运输机吗
As that fucking transport plane?
这是你杰作  罗伯特先生  你一手造成的
That is what you've accomplished, mr. roberts, single-handedly.
我有可靠的情报
I had good information.
我调查的目标正在用那架飞机走私毒品
That the target of my investigation was bringing dope in on that plane.
-目标是谁?  -弗兰克·卢卡斯
And that target is? frank lucas.
-谁?  -他叫弗兰克·卢卡斯
Who? his name's frank lucas.
谁是弗兰克·卢卡斯  他为谁工作?  为哪个家族?
Who is frank lucas? who does he work for? which family?
他不是意大利人  他是个黑人
He's not italian. he's black.
不是在开玩笑吧
Is that supposed to be some kind of a joke?
你的执法生涯已经接近尾声了
You're this close to the end of your career in law enforcement
你还在和我开玩笑?
And you're making fucking jokes?
我的调查显示
My investigation indicates
弗兰克·卢卡斯在毒品生意中凌驾于黑手党之上
That frank lucas is above the mafia in the dope business.
我的调查还显示
My investigations also indicate
弗兰克·卢卡斯从东南亚的一个毒品基地直接买货
That frank lucas buys direct from a source in southeast asia.
他跳过了中间人并且用美军飞机运输
He cuts out the middlemen and uses us military planes
向国内运送高纯度4号海洛因
And personnel to transport pure #4 heroin into the united states
而且从1969年开始他就这么干了
And he's been doing so on a regular basis since 1969.
我有弗兰克·卢卡斯团伙中每个成员的案底
I have cases against every member of frank's organization.
弗兰克·卢卡斯的团伙?
Frank's organization?
没有黑鬼能做到黑手党花了100年都没做成的事情
No fucking nigger has ever accomplished what the American mafia hasn't in 100 years
你知道为什么吗  就因为你他妈的是头蠢猪
And you would know that how? why? 'cause your head is stuck up your fucking ass?
嘿  帮我个忙  把这个该死的犹太佬赶出去
Hey, lou, do me a favor. will you get this fucking kike out of here?
犹太佬?  犹太佬?
Kike? kike?
瑞奇  不要
Richie, no.
嘿  瑞奇
Hey, richie!
坚持下去
Make it stick.
斯比尔曼在跟踪那些棺材  他们离这儿有四分之一英里远
Spearman's with the coffins. they're about a quarter mile away.
德克
Doctor.
怎么了?
What?
该死的特鲁普去家里捣乱了  兄弟  情况很糟
Fucking trupo came by the house, man. it's bad.
弗兰克  我有话要和你说
Frankie, I need to speak with you a minute. please?
-我要出去  妈妈  -不  等等  就一分钟
I got to go, ma. no, sit down just a minute.
你可以先出去一会儿吗
Would you please come back a little later?
谢谢
Thank you.
-妈我得走了  好吗?  -就几句话
Ma, I got to go. all right? just a few words.
听我说  我得...
Listen to me. I got...
拜托了  坐下  就几句话
Please, sit down. just a few words.
我一直在想这些事
I've been thinking about some things.
你知道  如果你是个布道者  你兄弟也会是布道者
If you'd been a preacher, your brothers would have been preachers.
是的
Right.
如果你是一名士兵  他们也会是士兵  你知道的
If you'd been a soldier, they'd be soldiers. you know that.
他们因你而来  是你打电话叫他们来投奔你
They came here because of you. you called and they came running.
是
Right.
那是因为他们都很崇拜你
That's because they look up to you.
他们一直认定你知道应该怎样做
They always expect you to know what's best.
就连他们也知道...
But even they know
你不会杀警察
You don't shoot cops.
这连我也知道
Even I know that.
-伊娃也知道  -好了  妈
Eva knows it. all right, ma.
看来唯一不清楚这一点的是你!
The only one who doesn't seem to know is you!
好了  妈  我要走了  我保证不会杀任何人
All right, ma. I got to go. I promise you, I ain't gonna shoot nobody.
我从没问过你这一切从哪来的  因为我不想听你说谎
I never asked you where all this came from because I didn't want to hear you lie.
我不想你担心  现在我得走了
I didn't want you to worry about it. now, come on, I got to go.
别对我说谎!
Don't lie to me!
别那样做
Don't do that.
你想把事情弄糟
Do you want to make things so bad
而让你的家人离你而去吗  他们会的
For your family that they'll leave you? because they will.
他们会理解的
They'll understand.
她会离开你
She will leave you.
好了  妈妈
All right, mama.
我也会离开你!
I will leave you!
棺材要被运走了  瑞奇
Got coffins on the move, richie.
我们要找的是运货的棺材  不是葬礼上的
We want the transport coffins, not the ceremonial ones.
这些人是谁?
Who are these guys?
写的什么?
What does it say?
贝永保管服务?
Bayonne custodial services?
贝永清洁服务?
Bayonne cleaning services?
贝永?  那是他妈的什么东西?
Bayonne? what the fuck is that?
给我望远镜  埃尔
Give me the camera, al.
我们中大奖了
Bingo.
妈的  是打棒球那小子
Holy shit. that's the baseball kid.
是啊  他叫施蒂夫·卢卡斯
Oh, yeah. that's stevie lucas.
你打算怎么办  瑞奇?  跟着卡车?
So what you want to do, richie? follow the trucks?
不  不  我要在这盯着卢卡斯
No. no. I wanna stay here with the lucas kid.
那我们跟踪货车
We'll follow that van.
你们最好都吃饱了  这会是个漫长的夜晚
You guys better eat up. we're gonna have a long night.
小心  伙计  这比黄金还贵重呢
Come on, more precious than gold, man.
这比黄金还贵重
This is more precious than gold.
还有几箱  抓紧装好
We got a couple more. let's go. stack that up.
运走  运走
Take it. take it.
马上就好  伙计  马上
Give me a second, man, give me a second.
嘿  还有4口棺材呢  伙计  一起发财吧
Hey. yo. we got four caskets left, man. let's make some fucking money in here.
他们在装什么?
What are they loading in there?
他妈的装什么呢?
What the fuck are they loading in there?
毒品
That's the dope.
一定是毒品  一定是
That's got to be the dope! it's got to be.
走吧
Let's go.
Let's move.
鲁  是我瑞奇
Lou, it's richie.
所有人都已就位  所有人
We got everybody in place. everybody.
你确定人赃俱在?
Are you sure this is it?
绝对肯定  放心
I'm positive, man. okay?
他们正在分割和打包
All right, they're cutting and bagging
他们正在史蒂芬克莱恩大厦的南楼
In the south tower of the stephen crane projects right now.
你能确定那就是目标吗?  你确定?
Are you sure this is it? you're positive?
我确定  我确定
I'm positive, lou. I'm positive. okay?
一切就绪  所有的人都准备好了
Everything is ready to go. all the guys are ready to go.
你就下命令吧  把搜查令给我们  好吗
Just push the button, give me the warrant, okay?
好的  给你
Okay. you got it.
一切顺利吗
You all right?
-拿到搜查令了  -好
Got the warrant. all right.
我们走
Let's go!
快点
Move!
-女士  怎么称呼  -这儿怎么了?
Hi, ma'am. what's your name? what's going on here?
趴下  趴下  笨蛋
Get down! get down, motherfucker!
我们走  埃尔
Go. okay. let's go, al!
这边  跟上
Move it, come on.
快  跟上  跟上
Come on, move it. move it!
全部就位
All set.
已收到
Roger.
准备好
Get ready.
来啊  好的
There you go! all right.
快点
Come on.
发现目标
At target.
斯比尔曼  原地待命
Spearman, stand by.
目标楼层里有平民
I got civilians on the target floor.
什么?
What? oh...
快点  又来了
Come on, there you go.
嘿  迪姆
Hey, tim.
辣妹  怎么不多穿点衣服
Girl, why don't you get some clothes on?
我们走
Let's go.
你知道你很坏  是吗
You think you bad, huh?
等一等  你要去哪?  去哪?
Hold on. where you going? where you going?
快点
Come on!
我去捡球
I'll get it!
迪姆呢?
Where's tim?
别说话  孩子
Quiet, kid!
我给你们弄了些三明治
I got some sandwiches for you boys, man.
迪姆跑哪儿去了
But where's tim?
妈的  他总是到处瞎逛
Shit. man, tim always playing around.
嘿  伙计
Hey, man!
有没有"蓝色梦幻"?
You got some blue magic, baby?
该死的瘾君子
Fucking junkie!
你  去处理一下
Yo, handle that!
我犯瘾了!  快点!  我有钱  老兄
I'm sick! come on! I got money, man!
来吧  伙计  你认识我的  宝贝儿
Come on, man, you know me, baby!
来吧!  快点  我需要"蓝色梦幻"  伙计
Come on! come on, I need that blue magic, man.
是我  宝哥啊  宝贝儿
It's me, boogaloo, baby.
嘿  伙计  你知道我有钱  快点
Hey, man, you know I got your god damn money. come on, man.
一  二  三  混蛋
And one, two, three! fucking junkie.
警察!  警察!
Police! police!
放下武器  趴下  趴下
Drop it! get out, get out!
-放下枪  -别动
Drop the gun! don't do it!
-放下枪  放下!  -别动
Drop the gun, drop it! don't do it.
斯哥特
Scotty!
警察!  都趴下!
Police! everybody down!
狗娘养的
You motherfucker!
警察!  都不许动!  当心
Police! nobody move! look out!
别他妈的动!
Don't fucking move!
把手举起来!  都把手举起来!
I want to see your hands! all the hands!
警察!
Police!
趴下!  趴下!
Down! down! get down!
都他妈趴下!
Stay the fuck down!
嘿  伙计  怎么了?
Hey, man, what's going on?
搞什么鬼?
What the hell...
趴下!  混蛋!  趴下!
Stay down! down, motherfucker! stay down!
手  手拿出来
Hands! hands!
回家了  孩子
Out at home, baby.
-非常感谢  -不客气
Thank you very much. you're welcome.
在这里等一下  等一下
Y'all wait right here. wait right here.
∮That saved a wretch∮
-卢卡斯夫人  请进屋去  -好的  长官
Mrs. lucas, please step back inside. yes, officer.
请  老夫人  请进屋去
Please, mother lucas, step inside, please.
麻烦您进去  谢谢
Respectfully, ma'am, please step inside. thank you. step inside.
-举起手来背靠墙  -都退后
Hands up against the wall. stay back.
伙计
Oh, man.
你不还欠我钱吗  我再给你拿点
Don't you owe me money? I'll get you some more. here you go.
你这猪!  当心!
Yo, yo! pigs! look out!
纽约警察!  谁都不许动
Nypd! everybody stand still!
特纳  快跑!
Turner! go!
趴下  混蛋
Down on the ground, motherfucker!
为国捐躯的烈士们回家了
...dead servicemen returning from defending our country in vietnam...
在那
Over there. okay.
女士们先生们  在诉讼阶段
Ladies and gentlemen, at this stage of the proceedings
双方律师已经准备好发表公开的陈述
The counsels are ready for their opening statements.
检方代表  罗伯特先生会率先
For the prosecution, mr. roberts will proceed
发表他的公开陈述
With his opening statement first.
罗伯特先生  你准备好发言了吗
Mr. roberts, are you ready to proceed?
是的  法官大人
Yes, your honor.
陪审团的女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
你们即将听到的这份发言会说明
The state will show and you will hear
弗兰克·卢卡斯是我们城市中
That frank lucas is the most dangerous man
最危险的人物
Walking the streets of our city.
你们都出去吧  让我和瑞奇先生单独谈谈
All right, y'all, get on out. let me talk to mr. richie alone.
快点  快点  我是按小时付你们钱的  不是按分钟
Come on, come on, come on. I pay y'all by the hour, not by the minute.
谢谢
Thank you.
你身上没装窃听器吧?
You ain't wearing a wire, are you?
没有
No.
好的
All right.
我和律师们谈过了  我不敢相信他们说的
I was talking to my lawyers. they said something to me, I can't believe it.
你真的把在车后箱发现的
Did you really find a million dollars in the trunk of a car
-一百万美金上缴了?  你这么做了?  -对
And then turn it in? did you do that? yeah.
你真这么做了?
You did that for real, huh?
伙计  好样的  妈的
My man. good for you. shit.
-你知道强尼·罗拿了这笔钱  对吗
You know johnny law got, though, right?
关于这事  瑞奇先生
About it, mr. richie.
你知道他拿了  他把你上缴的钱拿了
You know he got it. you turned that money in,
而你什么也捞不到  对吧?
He took it and you ain't get nothing for it. did you?
你为什么要这样做呢?
Why did you do that?
-我做的是正确的事  -这倒是真的
It was the right thing to do. that's true.
多好的答案  你所做的是正确的
That's a good answer. it was the right thing to do.
我一直在追问自己
The question I have, the question I've been asking myself is,
如果再有这种情况  你还会这样做吗
Would you do it again?
我的意思是  那是一大笔钱  而且也是很久以前了
I mean, that's a lot of money, that's a long time ago.
现在你也许有很多车贷要还  还要付孩子的抚养费
Many car payments ago, many child support payments ago.
所以我对自己说  找出答案的唯一方法就是再试一次
So I said to myself, the onlyest way to find out is to find out.
贿赂  敲诈  谋杀  诈骗...
Bribery, extortion, murder, racketeering...
如果你告诉我地址
Now, you give me an address,
我保证有辆车会停在那  钱就在后备箱里
I'll make sure the car's there, I'll make sure that money's in that trunk.
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
你确定?
You sure?
算了吧  瑞奇  你以为这样就能让我佩服你?
Come on, now, richie. what do you think, that impresses me?
你认为你比他们强?  其实好不到哪儿去
You think that you're better than them? you ain't no better than them other cops.
事实上  你和他们一样  你就是他们中的一员
In fact, you're the same as them. you are them.
我来问问你
Let me ask you this.
你真认为把我关进监狱
Do you really think that putting me behind bars
就能改变一切了
Is going to change anything on them streets?
那些隐君子们还是会继续吸毒
Them dope fiends is gonna shoot it,
他们会去偷窃  他们会为毒品而死
They're gonna steal for it, they're gonna die for it.
把我送进牢里改变不了任何事
Putting me in or out ain't gonna change one thing.
事实就是如此
Then that's the way it is.
事实如此  我们又得到了什么呢  瑞奇?
That's just the way it is. so what we got, richie?
你我坐在这里
We got me and you sitting here.
还有那个帮我兄弟开车的告密司机
We got that little snitch-ass driver for my brother.
你还找到了一些白粉
You got a little bit of powder.
你要的远不止这些  瑞奇
You're going to need more than that, richie.
我知道赃物  货源  同谋  贿赂检察官
I got possession, supply, conspiracy,
我有人证看到你残忍杀人
Bribing a law officer. I got people who'll attest to seeing you kill in cold blood.
我有你海外银行的帐户  你的不动产  你的生意
I got your offshore bank accounts, your real estate, your businesses,
都是你卖海洛因得到的钱
All bought with money from heroin.
我有上百个失去孩子的父母
And I got hundreds of parents of dead kids.
孩子因为你的毒品而上瘾  这就是我要告诉陪审团的
Addicts who od'ed on your product. and that's my story for the jury.
这就是我为何如此坚持  你谋杀了数千条人命
And that's how I make it all stick. "this man murdered thousands of people.
却享受着豪宅  开着林肯车
"and he did it from a penthouse, driving a lincoln."
除了这些  你没什么好担心的
Aside from that, you got nothing to worry about.
干的不错  那就是我们上法庭的目的  对吧?  瑞奇
That's pretty good. but that's why we go to court, isn't it, richie?
因为我也有证人
Cause I got witnesses, too.
我有娱乐明星  体育明星  我掌握了哈林区
I got celebrities. I got sports figures. I got harlem, richie.
我罩着哈林区  所以哈林区也会支持我  你要相信这点
I took care of harlem, so harlem's gonna take care of me. you can believe that.
-我还有更多的  弗兰克  -你还有什么?
I got more than that, frank. what you got?
我还有一票人想要指证你
I've got a line of people wanting to testify against you,
他们挤破了门  围满了街头
It stretches out the door and around the block.
你毁了无数生命  弗兰克  我有玛扎诺犯罪家族
You damaged a lot of lives, frank. I got the mazzano crime family.
还记得那些家伙吗  你让他们破了产
Remember those boys? you put them out of business.
我与玛扎诺家族毫无关系
I ain't got nothing to do with no mazzanos.
玛扎诺家族和我也没半点牵连
Mazzanos ain't got nothing to do with me.
他们和你的关系太大了  他们要扳倒你
They got everything to do with you. what, they...
-你知道为什么吗  -为什么
You know why? why?
因为他们实际上对你恨之入骨
Because apart from the fact that they hate you personally,
恨你所代表的
They hate what you represent.
-我谁也不代表  除了我自己  -你确定?
I don't represent nothing but frank lucas. you sure?
像你这样的黑人商人
A black businessman like you?
你代表的是进步
You represent progress.
这种进步会让他们损失惨重
The kind of progress that's going to see them lose a lot of money.
你消失了  一切都会恢复正常
With you out of the way, everything can return to normal.
兄弟啊
My man.
你知道正常对我来说意味着什么?
You know what normal is to me, richie?
我6岁起就没见过正常的事
I ain't seen normal since I was six years old.
正常的事是目睹警察来到我家
Normal is seeing the police right up to my house
拖走我仅12岁的堂兄  把他绑在柱子上
Dragging my little 12-year-old cousin out, tying him to a pole,
用枪在他嘴里猛捣  把他的牙都打碎了
Shoving a shotgun in his mouth so hard they bust his teeth.
接着对他的头来了两枪
Then they bust two shotgun shells in his head and knock his fucking head off.
那对我来说就是正常的事
That's what normal is to me.
从那时开始我就鄙视警察...
I didn't give a fuck about no police then.
现在我也同样鄙视警察  妈的
I don't give a fuck about no police now. shit.
你知道的  你可以为所欲为
You know what, you can do whatever you want to do.
不过这对我来说没有任何意义
So, it don't mean nothing to me for you to show up tomorrow morning
因为明早你就会脑袋开花  你明白我说的吗
With your head blown off. do you understand what I'm saying?
弗兰克  规矩点
Yeah, frank. get in line.
那只会让你罪加一等
That one stretches around the block, too.
好吧
All right.
你想怎样?
What do you want to do?
你知道该怎么做
You know what you got to do.
你想要我干什么?  做污点证人?
What do you want me to do? snitch, huh?
我知道你不想让我供出警察
I know you don't want me to give up no cops.
你想要什么?  黑帮分子?
What do you want? you want gangsters?
挑一个吧  犹太帮?  爱尔兰帮?  法国帮?
Pick one. jew gangsters? mick gangsters? guineas?
他们从来美国开始就在哈林区大开杀戒
They've been bleeding harlem dry since they got off the boat, richie.
我他妈的不在乎这些犯罪分子  你可以抓他们
I don't give a fuck about no crime figures. you can have them.
这些我也要
I'll take them, too.
这些你也要?
You'll take them, too?
你不会吧  你说的是警察  你想要警察?
No, you didn't. you're talking about police. you want police?
你要抓自己人?
You want your own kind?
他们不是我自己人
They're not my kind.
他们和你做交易  弗兰克  他们不是自己人
They're in business with you, frank. they ain't my kind.
他们不是自己人  就好比意大利人不是你自己人一样
They ain't my kind like the italians are not yours. all right?
也对
Huh.
你能给我什么承诺  瑞奇?
What can you promise me, richie?
我可以承诺的是  你要是隐瞒了一个名字
I can promise you, you lie about one name,
你就永远别想从监狱里出来
You'll never get out of prison.
你隐瞒哪怕是一美元
You lie about one dollar,
一个海外帐户  就永远别想出来
in one offshore account, you'll never get out of prison.
你可以选择在监狱中富裕的度过余生
Now you can live life rich in jail for the rest of your born days,
还是穷困的活在监狱外
Or be poor outside for some of them.
这是我能给你的承诺
That's what I can promise you.
我要你抓住那些警察  瑞奇 我想要你抓住他们
I want them cops, richie. that's what I want, I want them cops
那些从我兜里拿钱的警察
That took that money out of my pockets.
他也是
Him, too.
很好
All right. okay.
嘿  斯比尔曼
Hey, spearman? spearman.
这些全是有关联的
So these guys are all connected up to gywnn, all right.
这个人  他是个警察
See this guy here, he's in uniform...
警方今天逮捕了4名涉嫌
Newscaster 1: four police officers were arrested today
接受毒枭贿赂的警员
On charges of taking bribes from drug traffickers.
干的好  吉米
Well done, jimmy.
关于警界腐败的调查
Newscaster 2: the investigation into police corruption
正在席卷整个纽约缉毒组
Has swept through new york's drug enforcement ranks
今天又逮捕了19个警员
Broadened today with the arrest of 19 more officers.
据称这是纽约市最大的警察受贿丑闻
Newscaster 3: in what is being called this city's largest police corruption scandal,
今天将有超过32名警员因为受贿而在联邦法院接受指控
32 more officers were indicted today in federal court on bribery charges.
这些警察将面临牢狱之灾
Newscaster 4: these police officers will face stiff prison terms,
联邦检查官认为这些警察有罪
Say federal prosecutors, if found guilty.
一份有关纽约事件的联邦调查报告表明
Newscaster 5: a report by federal investigators into new york's
警察受贿丑闻日渐扩大
Everwidening police corruption scandal
据称有超过半数的负责缉毒的
Claims that more than half of the city's officers
市政官员卷入类似腐败
Assigned to drug enforcement have engaged in some form of corruption.
关于缉毒组精英的反麻醉品分队
Newscaster 6: allegations of widespread corruption within
普遍受贿的指控
The elite narcotics squad siu
导致更多的纽约骨干探员被捕
Have led to the arrest of more new york city detectives.
他们被证明犯有勒索罪
convicted of extortion,
纽约特别缉毒组成员
Members of new york city's special investigations narcotics unit
今天将面临联邦法庭的宣判
Will face sentencing today in federal court.
麦克纳马拉·文达索
Macnamara. vendazzo.
特鲁普
Trupo.
你的确是个特例
You are special.
干的漂亮  弗兰克
It's good work, frank.
你...
You know...
你不想喝点什么来庆祝一下?
You don't want a drink or something? celebrate?
你有圣水吗
You got any holy water?
弗兰克·卢卡斯被判阴谋贩毒
罪名成立，入狱70年
联邦机构没收了弗兰克·卢卡斯在美国
及海外银行超过2.5亿美元的资产
弗兰克和瑞奇的合作使四分之三
的纽约扫毒局探员被判有罪
弗兰克家族30名成员
以运毒罪被判入狱
弗兰克的妻子回到波多黎各
弗兰克的母亲搬回了北卡
瑞奇·罗伯斯从检察官
办公室辞职成为辩护律师
(他的第一个客户是弗兰克·卢卡斯)
检查你的物品  在这里签字
Check your property. sign, please.
由于他的合作，弗兰克·卢卡斯
的刑期被减为15年，于1991年获释
外面的空气如何?
Smell better out here?
弗兰克  给你
Frank. there you are.
拿铁咖啡
Caffe latte. yeah.
拿铁?
Latte?
该死
Oh, shit. yeah.
你还好吗?
You all right?
这是对牛奶咖啡的时髦叫法
That's a fancy way of saying coffee with milk.
2.5美元
Yeah. $2.50.
你一直和兄弟们保持联系?
So you been talking to your brothers?
没  我好多年都不和他们说话了
No, no, I ain't talked to them in years.
那可能对他们更好
It's probably best for them.
我能干什么呢  瑞奇?
What the hell am I going to do out here, richie?
不知道我该以何为生
I don't know how I'm gonna live.
嘿  我跟你说  我不会让你挨饿的
Hey, I told ya, I ain't gonna let you starve, all right?
很显然  你没挨饿
Obviously, you ain't starving.
知道吗  巴格斯和布林奇也快出来了
Bagels and blinches they will catch up with you, you know?
这是什么?
Who's this?
奢侈的运动鞋  一百美金一双
Expensive sneakers. about $100 a pair.
弗雷德里克·道格拉斯大道
Frederick douglass boulevard.
这以前是第八大道
This used to be eighth avenue, why do they call it
为什么现在改名了
Frederick douglass boulevard now?
这以前是我的  瑞奇  就是这
This was me richie, right here.
这都是我的
This was all me.
在我的时代这有许多黑人来买毒品
In my day there were so many niggers out here buying dope
你可以拍一部传奇电影
You could've made a tarzan movie.
你知道  一个电话我就可以重振雄风
You know, one phone call, I'll be right back in business, you know that.
别这样  弗兰克
You don't do that, frank.
这些年我都信守承诺
These days I keep all my promises.
为什么来接我?
Why'd you come and get me, huh?
你是个超级明星  弗兰克
You're a superstar, frank.
超级明星?
A superstar?
你的证据让我定了150个人的罪
Your evidence alone gave me 150 convictions.
我想我至少能送你回家
Thought the least we could do is give you a ride home.
是啊  你是那么做的
Yeah, you sure did that.
你送我回家  免费的
You gave me a ride home. free ride.
来接黑帮老大出狱
Coming to gangsters.
干什么?
What?
没事儿  没事儿  伙计
Ain't nothin', man. ain't nothin', man.
那就是这儿的生活
That's life right there. that's life right there.
即使是个傻子也年轻过
Even a fool gets to be young once.